WASHINGTON B-Gpe
: O
China B-Gpe
is O
besting O
the O
United B-Org
States I-Org
in O
key O
military O
technologies O
like O
hypersonic O
missiles O
and O
electronic O
warfare, O
Gen. O
Paul B-Person
Selva I-Person
, O
vice-chairman O
of O
the O
Joint B-Org
Chiefs I-Org
said O
today. O
We O
can O
still O
catch O
up, O
he O
predicted. O
What O
about O
Artificial B-ai_tec
Intelligence I-ai_tec
? O
That's O
too O
close O
to O
call, O
said O
former O
deputy O
Defense O
Secretary O
Bob B-Person
Work I-Person
, O
so O
we'd O
better O
get O
a O
move O
on. O
Both O
men O
spoke O
at O
a O
CNAS B-MISC
conference O
on O
" O
Strategic B-MISC
Competition: I-MISC
Maintaining I-MISC
The I-MISC
Edge. I-MISC
" O
"I O
actually O
regret O
talking O
about O
the O
Third B-Date
Offset I-Date
Strategy I-Date
, O
in O
hindsight," O
Work B-Person
said, O
referring O
to O
the O
high-tech O
initiative O
he O
launched O
in O
the O
Obama B-Org
Pentagon I-Org
. O
"It O
made O
it O
sound O
like O
we O
had O
the O
advantage O
and O
we O
had O
the O
time O
to O
think O
about O
it O
and O
go O
through O
the O
motions…. O
I O
wish O
I O
would O
have O
said, O
'we O
need O
to O
start O
about O
upsetting O
the O
Chinese B-Gpe
offset, O
which O
is O
coming O
uncomfortably O
close O
to O
achieving O
technological O
parity O
with O
the O
US B-Gpe
.' O
"At O
this O
point, O
I O
would O
think O
that O
the O
outcome O
is O
too O
close O
to O
call," O
Work B-Person
said. O
"It's O
time O
for O
the O
US B-Gpe
to O
crack O
the O
whip. O
(Let's) O
hope O
it's O
not O
too O
late." O
So O
what O
are O
some O
of O
these O
shortfalls? O
The O
most O
high-profile O
is O
hypersonics, O
weapons O
designed O
to O
move O
through O
the O
atmosphere O
at O
more O
than O
five O
times O
the O
speed O
of O
sound. O
Defense B-Org
Undersecretary I-Org
for O
R&D O
Mike B-Person
Griffin I-Person
has O
made O
hypersonics O
his O
top O
priority O
and O
has O
warned O
that O
China B-Gpe
has O
conducted O
20 O
times O
more O
tests O
than O
the O
US B-Gpe
. O
China B-Gpe
has O
demonstrated O
some O
impressive O
technology, O
Gen. O
Selva B-Person
said O
today, O
but O
the O
race O
is O
far O
from O
over. O
"They O
haven't O
mass-deployed O
hypersonics O
or O
long-range O
ballistic O
missiles," O
he O
said. O
"What O
they O
have O
done O
is O
proven O
the O
technologies, O
so O
they O
are O
able O
now O
to O
deploy O
those O
capabilities O
on O
a O
larger O
scale. O
"We O
are O
behind O
in O
the O
demonstration O
of O
many O
of O
those O
technologies," O
Selva B-Person
admitted, O
elaborating O
on O
a O
statement O
he O
made O
in O
January, O
"but O
we O
also O
can O
take O
asymmetric O
approaches O
and O
catch O
up. O
We O
are O
way O
ahead O
in O
a O
lot O
of O
the O
sensor O
integration O
technologies" O
— O
essential O
for O
telling O
the O
hyper-fast O
weapons O
where O
to O
go O
— O
"and O
we O
have O
to O
maintain O
that O
edge." O
What O
about O
Electronic B-Date
Warfare I-Date
, O
I O
asked? O
Detecting, O
triangulating, O
and O
jamming O
enemy O
radio O
transmissions O
has O
long O
been O
a O
Russian B-Gpe
strength O
and O
is O
increasingly O
a O
Chinese B-Gpe
one, O
while O
the O
US B-Gpe
disbanded O
many O
of O
its O
EW B-Org
forces I-Org
after O
the O
Cold B-MISC
War I-MISC
. O
Selva B-Person
's O
answer O
got O
into O
technical O
nuances O
I O
hadn't O
heard O
before. O
"We're O
a O
step O
behind," O
Selva B-Person
said. O
"It's O
not O
hard O
to O
catch O
up, O
but O
as O
soon O
as O
you O
catch O
up O
the O
fast O
followers O
will O
actually O
leap O
over O
the O
top O
of O
you O
— O
and O
that's O
the O
dynamic O
that's O
set O
up O
by O
having O
digital O
radio O
frequency O
management O
capability." O
DRFM B-ai_product
, O
also O
called O
Digital B-ai_product
Radio I-ai_product
Frequency I-ai_product
Memory I-ai_product
, O
uses O
modern O
computing O
power O
to O
record O
enemy O
radio O
and O
radar O
signals, O
modify O
them, O
and O
copy O
them, O
allowing O
forces O
to O
transmit O
a O
false O
signal O
that O
the O
enemy O
can't O
tell O
from O
the O
real O
thing. O
It's O
a O
much O
more O
effective O
way O
of O
"spoofing" O
than O
traditional O
analog O
techniques, O
which O
suffered O
from O
telltale O
signal O
degradation. O
"We O
assumed O
wrongly O
that O
encryption O
and O
our O
domination O
in O
the O
precision O
timing O
signals O
would O
allow O
us O
to O
evade O
the O
enemy O
in O
the O
electromagnetic O
spectrum," O
Selva B-Person
said. O
It O
turns O
that O
that O
timing O
is O
everything O
in O
EW B-Org
as O
well O
as O
comedy. O
While O
GPS B-MISC
is O
now O
part O
of O
daily O
life, O
a O
much O
less O
well-known O
feature O
is O
that O
GPS B-MISC
requires O
incredibly O
precise O
timing O
— O
within O
about O
three-billionths O
of O
a O
second O
— O
which O
can O
be O
used O
for O
other O
purposes, O
such O
as O
coordinating O
different O
radios O
as O
they O
switch O
rapidly O
from O
one O
frequency O
to O
another O
to O
avoid O
enemy O
detection O
and O
jamming. O
But O
apparently O
that O
wasn't O
enough O
to O
evade O
DRFM B-ai_product
-based O
jamming, O
which O
can O
create O
a O
false O
timing O
signal O
that O
causes O
the O
entire O
network O
to O
fall O
out O
of O
synch. O
"We O
took O
a O
path O
that O
they O
have O
now O
figured O
out," O
Selva B-Person
said. O
"The O
Chinese B-Gpe
and O
the O
Russian B-Gpe
s O
took O
an O
alternative O
path, O
which O
was O
to O
employ O
digitally O
managed O
radio O
frequency O
manipulation, O
which O
changed O
the O
game O
in O
electronic B-MISC
warfare I-MISC
. O

