"We O
have O
done O
an O
in-depth O
study O
of O
where O
we O
are O
relative O
to O
the O
Chinese B-Gpe
and O
Russians B-Gpe
(across) O
the O
entire O
spectrum, O
and O
we've O
got O
some O
work O
to O
do," O
Selva O
said. O
"We O
have O
to O
figure O
out O
alternative O
pathways O
for O
communications O
and O
command O
and O
control O
so O
it O
doesn't O
have O
to O
be O
an O
RF O
(Radio O
Frequency) O
game…It's O
an O
RF O
game O
because O
we O
chose O
to O
make O
it O
so." O
He O
didn't O
specify O
what O
the O
alternatives O
to O
radio O
communication O
were, O
but O
there's O
been O
promising O
work O
using O
lasers O
to O
beam O
messages. O
(Breaking O
D O
readers O
will O
remember O
that O
we O
first O
reported O
the O
demise O
of O
America's O
lead O
in O
spectrum O
four O
years O
ago.) O
Securing O
our O
communications O
networks O
isn't O
enough, O
Work O
told O
me O
afterwards, O
because O
every O
weapon O
system O
now O
has O
chips O
in O
it O
that O
can O
be O
hacked O
into. O
"We O
have O
focused O
on O
securing O
network O
communications, O
but O
our O
biggest O
vulnerabilities O
now, O
Sydney, O
are O
in O
the O
DoD O
Internet O
of O
Things O
— O
the O
way O
you O
can O
crack O
into O
the O
network O
through O
platforms O
(e.g. O
tanks, O
aircraft, O
ships) O
and O
through O
components O
on O
platforms," O
Work O
said. O
"The O
Russians B-Gpe
and O
the O
Chinese B-Gpe
understand O
these O
vulnerabilities O
and O
really O
try O
to O
exploit O
them." O
So O
there O
are O
really O
three O
fronts O
in O
cyber/electronic O
warfare, O
and O
Work B-Person
isn't O
sanguine O
about O
any O
of O
them. O
"Dominating O
the O
electromagnetic O
spectrum, O
and O
securing O
the O
DoD B-Org
Internet O
of O
Things, O
and O
securing O
networks, O
all O
of O
these O
three O
things, O
in O
my O
view, O
we're O
well O
behind O
in," O
he O
told O
me. O
The O
whole O
" O
Chinese B-Gpe
theory O
of O
victory," O
he O
said, O
is O
known O
(in O
translation) O
as O
"systems O
destruction O
warfare" O
because O
it O
focuses O
on O
electronically O
paralyzing O
command-and-control O
rather O
than O
physically O
destroying O
tanks, O
ships, O
and O
planes. O
Now, O
artificial B-ai_tec
intelligence I-ai_tec
could O
potentially O
revolutionize O
electronic B-MISC
warfare I-MISC
. O
Computers O
can O
identify O
signals, O
trace O
them, O
and O
making O
jamming O
decisions O
much O
faster O
than O
human O
minds O
— O
a O
concept O
called O
"cognitive O
EW." O
But O
that's O
just O
one O
of O
the O
many O
military O
applications O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
, O
from O
advising O
human O
commanders O
to O
coordinating O
swarms O
of O
combat B-ai_product
robots I-ai_product
. O
While O
Selva B-Person
didn't O
address O
Artificial B-ai_tec
Intelligence I-ai_tec
, O
Work B-Person
did; O
it's O
one O
of O
his O
passions O
and O
the O
central O
theme O
of O
the O
(now O
deprecated) O
Third B-MISC
Offset I-MISC
Strategy I-MISC
. O
So O
who's O
ahead O
in O
AI B-ai_tec
? O
Defense B-Org
Innovation I-Org
Advisory I-Org
Board I-Org
chairman O
Eric B-Person
Schmidt I-Person
, O
a O
former O
Google B-Org
AI B-ai_tec
guru, O
told O
Work B-Person
he O
had O
once O
thought O
the O
US B-Gpe
was O
five O
years O
ahead O
of O
the O
Chinese B-Gpe
, O
Work B-Person
recounted. O
But O
after O
a O
recent O
trip O
to O
China B-Gpe
, O
Work B-Person
recounted, O
Schmidt B-Person
changed O
his O
verdict: O
"If O
we O
have O
six O
months, O
we're O
lucky." O
Schmidt B-Person
said O
last O
year O
that O
the O
US B-Gpe
lacks O
a O
coherent O
strategy O
to O
counter O
the O
Chinese B-Gpe
in O
this O
area. O
The O
US B-Gpe
has O
never O
been O
in O
a O
competition O
this O
intense, O
Work B-Person
said. O
China B-Gpe
has O
made O
AI B-ai_tec
an O
official O
national O
priority O
— O
something O
he O
thinks O
the O
White B-Org
House I-Org
should O
do O
here O
— O
and O
the O
Chinese B-Gpe
have O
great O
coders. O
The O
Pentagon B-Org
is O
now O
creating O
a O
Joint B-Org
Artificial I-Org
Intelligence I-Org
Center I-Org
, O
something O
Schmidt B-Person
's O
DIB O
proposed O
over O
a O
year O
ago, O
Work B-Person
noted. O
"We've O
got O
a O
lot O
of O
advantages O
and O
we O
can O
do O
very, O
very O
well O
in O
this O
race O
but O
don't O
take O
anything O
for O
granted," O
Work B-Person
told O
me. O
Just O
as O
politicians O
are O
warned O
never O
to O
take O
victory O
for O
granted, O
neither O
should O
DoD B-Org
. O
"It's O
a O
political O
rule O
to O
always O
run O
like O
you're O
losing, O
and O
that's O
what O
we O
have O
to O
do O
in O
this O
area….The O
Chinese B-Gpe
are O
very O
clever O
and O
very O
capable O
competitors, O
and O
they're O
intent O
on O
surpassing O
us." O

