Challenges O
associated O
with O
the O
use O
of O
artificial B-ai_tec
intelligence I-ai_tec
throughout O
the O
federal B-Org
government I-Org
include O
eliminating O
bias, O
preparing O
the O
workforce O
and O
defining O
ethical O
use. O
But O
increased O
use O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
also O
poses O
a O
challenge O
to O
inspectors O
general: O
How O
do O
they O
provide O
oversight O
of O
this O
technology? O
The O
inspector O
general O
for O
the O
Office O
of O
the O
Director O
of O
National B-Org
Intelligence I-Org
detailed O
in O
its O
Semiannual B-MISC
Report I-MISC
, O
released O
Nov. B-Date
25 I-Date
, O
how O
it's O
working O
to O
improve O
AI B-ai_tec
programs O
within O
the O
intelligence O
community. O
According O
the O
report, O
the O
IG B-MISC
s O
in O
the O
intel B-MISC
community I-MISC
face O
"mounting" O
challenges O
posed O
by O
discovering, O
sorting O
and O
analyzing O
large O
amounts O
of O
data. O
Thus, O
the O
inspector O
general O
of O
the O
intelligence O
community, O
or O
ICIG B-MISC
, O
"selected O
artificial B-ai_tec
intelligence I-ai_tec
as O
an O
objective O
for O
review O
due O
to O
the O
presence O
it O
has O
played O
in O
multiple O
documents O
and O
reports O
published O
by O
ODNI B-Org
." O
To O
better O
communication O
between O
IG B-MISC
s O
across O
the O
intel B-MISC
community I-MISC
, O
the O
ICIG B-MISC
has O
"begun O
exploring" O
the O
creation O
of O
an O
IG B-MISC
community O
of O
interest O
to O
induce O
collaboration O
between O
several O
IG B-MISC
offices, O
including O
those O
of O
the O
departments O
of O
Justice, O
State, O
Defense, O
Energy O
and O
Treasury, O
as O
well O
as O
the O
FBI. O
To O
better O
the O
ICIG B-MISC
's O
understanding O
of O
the O
how O
the O
intel B-MISC
community I-MISC
uses O
AI B-ai_tec
, O
and O
to O
enhance O
the O
inspectors O
general's O
audit O
capabilities, O
the O
ICIG B-MISC
has O
turned O
to O
government O
experts, O
academia O
and O
industry O
to O
begin O
"mapping O
the O
landscape" O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
-related O
work O
happening O
under O
its O
purview. O
The O
intel B-MISC
community I-MISC
is O
working O
on O
AI B-ai_tec
projects O
under O
a O
strategy O
document O
created O
under O
former O
Director O
of O
National B-Org
Intelligence I-Org
Dan B-Person
Coats I-Person
, O
titled O
" O
Augmenting B-ai_program
Intelligence I-ai_program
using I-ai_program
Machines I-ai_program
( O
AIM B-ai_program
) O
Initiative." O
That O
strategy O
identified O
AI B-ai_tec
as O
a O
technology O
that O
could O
improve O
data O
interpretation O
and O
mission O
capability. O
As O
different O
intel O
agencies O
moved O
forward O
with O
AI B-ai_tec
projects, O
the O
ICIG B-MISC
began O
compiling O
a O
list O
of O
existing O
and O
planned O
AI B-ai_tec
projects. O
The O
list, O
combined O
with O
other O
ICIG B-MISC
efforts O
to O
engage O
with O
AI B-ai_tec
efforts O
across O
government O
and O
industry, O
will O
"advance O
Intelligence B-Org
Community I-Org
Offices I-Org
of I-Org
Inspectors I-Org
General I-Org
's O
ability O
to O
develop O
criteria O
and O
measures O
for O
evaluating O
investments O
in O
oversight O
of O
artificial B-ai_tec
intelligence I-ai_tec
in O
terms O
of O
personnel, O
training, O
and O
technology." O
The O
use O
of O
emerging O
technology O
also O
presents O
the O
ICIG B-MISC
with O
workforce O
challenges. O
The O
ICIG B-MISC
has O
compiled O
a O
list O
of O
available O
course O
offerings O
within O
the O
government O
and O
academia O
that O
could O
"substantively O
broaden O
and O
deepen" O
the O
inspectors O
general's O
expertise O
in O
data O
and O
AI B-ai_tec
. O
The O
ICIG B-MISC
has O
also O
"expanded" O
its O
previous O
engagements O
with O
the O
Council B-Org
of I-Org
the I-Org
Inspectors I-Org
General I-Org
on O
Integrity O
and O
Efficiency, O
an O
federal O
inspectors O
general O
group O
working O
to O
better O
government O
IG B-MISC
offices. O
The O
ICIG B-MISC
pointed O
to O
the O
group's O
data O
analytics O
working O
group O
and O
its O
emerging O
technology O
subcommittee O
as O
important O
areas O
for O
the O
ICIG B-MISC
to O
engage. O
"The O
ICIG B-MISC
continues O
its O
work O
to O
enable O
shared O
situational O
awareness O
within O
the O
Inspector B-Org
General I-Org
community I-Org
, O
both O
in O
the O
Intelligence B-Org
Community I-Org
and O
the O
broader O
federal B-Org
government I-Org
," O
the O
report O
read. O

