The O
Sierra B-Org
Nevada I-Org
Corporation I-Org
has O
been O
selected O
for O
the O
final O
phase O
of O
the O
Defense B-Org
Advanced I-Org
Research I-Org
Agency I-Org
's O
Gremlins B-ai_program
program I-ai_program
, O
which O
aims O
to O
launch O
and O
recover O
reusable O
drone O
swarms O
using O
manned O
airborne O
aircraft O
far O
outside O
of O
enemy O
ranges, O
according O
to O
a O
May B-Date
9 I-Date
press O
release O
from O
the O
company. O
Sierra B-Org
Nevada I-Org
Corporation I-Org
( O
SNC B-Org
) O
will O
provide O
Gremlin B-ai_product
Air I-ai_product
Vehicles I-ai_product
with O
an O
autonomous B-ai_product
docking I-ai_product
system I-ai_product
, O
allowing O
the O
drones O
to O
be O
retrieved O
by O
a O
C-130 B-MISC
transport I-MISC
aircraft I-MISC
they O
complete O
their O
mission. O
They O
would O
then O
be O
carried O
home O
and O
prepared O
for O
reuse O
within O
24 O
hours. O
SNC B-Org
was O
selected O
for O
the O
program's O
Phase O
3 O
team O
by O
Dynetics B-Org
, O
an O
aeronautics O
company. O
Dynetics B-Org
is O
developing O
a O
capture O
device O
to O
be O
deployed O
below O
and O
away O
from O
a O
C-130 B-MISC
and O
then O
docked O
to O
the O
Gremlin B-ai_product
vehicles I-ai_product
, O
so O
they O
can O
be O
raised O
and O
returned O
to O
the O
transport O
aircraft O
mid-flight. O
The O
third O
and O
final O
phase O
of O
the O
program O
will O
serve O
as O
an O
opportunity O
to O
demonstrate O
the O
Gremlin B-ai_tec
technology I-ai_tec
developed O
during O
the O
two O
prior O
competitive O
phases, O
which O
narrowed O
competition O
down O
from O
four O
teams O
to O
one. O
" O
SNC B-Org
's O
past O
accomplishments O
with O
autonomous B-ai_tec
refueling I-ai_tec
and O
precision B-ai_tec
navigation I-ai_tec
were O
a O
perfect O
fit O
for O
what O
Dynetics B-Org
planned O
to O
accomplish O
on O
the O
Gremlins B-ai_program
program I-ai_program
," O
said O
Greg B-Person
Cox I-Person
, O
senior O
vice O
president O
of O
business O
development O
and O
technology O
for O
SNC B-Org
's O
electronic O
and O
information O
systems O
business O
area. O
The O
multivehicle O
control O
services O
and O
user O
interface O
for O
the O
vehicles O
will O
be O
provided O
by O
a O
third O
team O
member, O
Kutta B-Org
Technology I-Org
, O
also O
an O
SNC B-Org
subsidiary. O
Kutta B-Org
's O
role O
is O
to O
"provide O
a O
control O
station O
with O
safe, O
intuitive O
work O
flows O
for O
controlling O
multiple O
[ O
Gremlin B-ai_product
air I-ai_product
vehicles I-ai_product
] O
simultaneously O
from O
launch O
to O
recovery." O
Earlier O
this O
month O
DARPA B-Org
announced O
they O
had O
successfully O
tested O
Gremlin B-ai_tec
technology I-ai_tec
during O
a O
flight O
test O
at O
Yuma B-MISC
Proving I-MISC
Ground I-MISC
, O
keeping O
the O
program O
on O
path O
toward O
airborne O
launch O
and O
recovery O
of O
multiple O
drones O
by O
late B-Date
2019 I-Date
. O
"Early O
flight O
tests O
have O
given O
us O
confidence O
we O
can O
meet O
our O
objective O
to O
recover O
four O
gremlins O
in O
30 O
minutes," O
said O
Scott B-Person
Wierzbanowski I-Person
, O
program O
manager O
in O
DARPA B-Org
's O
Tactical B-Org
Technology I-Org
Office I-Org
. O
DARPA B-Org
awarded O
Dynetics B-Org
a O
21-month, O
$38.6 O
million O
contract O
for O
the O
third O
phase O
the O
Gremlin B-ai_program
program I-ai_program
in O
April B-Date
. O
Other O
members O
of O
the O
team O
include O
Kratos B-Org
Unmanned I-Org
Aerial I-Org
Systems I-Org
, O
Moog B-Org
, O
Airborne B-Org
Systems I-Org
, O
Systima B-Org
, O
Applied B-Org
Systems I-Org
Engineering I-Org
, O
Inc., O
and O
International B-Org
Air I-Org
Response I-Org
. O

