WASHINGTON B-Gpe
– O
The O
Defense B-Org
Department I-Org
has O
formally O
ordered O
the O
creation O
of O
a O
new O
hub O
for O
artificial B-ai_tec
intelligence I-ai_tec
research O
with O
Dana B-Person
Deasy I-Person
, O
the O
Pentagon's O
new O
chief O
information O
officer, O
taking O
the O
lead. O
Deputy O
Secretary O
of O
Defense O
Patrick B-Person
Shanahan I-Person
ordered O
the O
move O
in O
a O
June B-Date
27 I-Date
memo. O
The O
Pentagon B-Org
's O
goal O
is O
to O
launch O
a O
series O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
projects O
known O
as O
National B-ai_program
Mission I-ai_program
Initiatives I-ai_program
within O
90 O
days O
– O
as O
well O
as O
taking O
over O
the O
controversial O
Project B-ai_program
Maven I-ai_program
. O
The O
office O
will O
be O
known O
as O
the O
Joint B-Org
Artificial I-Org
Intelligence I-Org
Center I-Org
( O
JAIC B-Org
), O
with O
the O
goal O
of O
enabling O
"teams O
across O
DoD B-Org
to O
swiftly O
deliver O
new O
AI B-ai_tec
-enabled O
capabilities O
and O
effectively O
experiment O
with O
new O
operating O
concepts O
in O
support O
of O
DoD B-Org
's O
military O
missions O
and O
business O
functions," O
according O
to O
DoD B-Org
spokeswoman O
Lt. O
Col. O
Michelle B-Person
Baldanza I-Person
. O
Put O
another O
way, O
the O
group O
will O
have O
the O
"overarching O
goal O
of O
accelerating O
the O
delivery O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
-enabled O
capabilities, O
scaling O
the O
Department-wide O
impact O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
, O
and O
synchronizing O
DoD B-Org
AI B-ai_tec
activities O
to O
expand O
Joint B-Org
Force I-Org
advantages," O
according O
to O
a O
copy O
of O
the O
memo O
posted O
by O
Breaking B-Org
Defense I-Org
. O
"This O
effort O
is O
a O
Department O
priority. O
Speed O
and O
security O
are O
of O
the O
essence," O
Shanahan B-Person
wrote. O
"I O
expect O
all O
offices O
and O
personnel O
to O
provide O
all O
reasonable O
support O
necessary O
to O
make O
rapid O
enterprise-wide O
AI B-ai_tec
adoption O
a O
reality." O
Deputy O
Secretary O
of O
Defense O
Patrick B-Person
M. I-Person
Shanahan I-Person
directed O
the O
DoD B-Org
Chief O
Information O
Officer O
to O
standup O
the O
Joint B-Org
Artificial I-Org
Intelligence I-Org
Center I-Org
( O
JAIC B-Org
) O
in O
order O
to O
enable O
teams O
across O
DoD B-Org
to O
swiftly O
deliver O
new O
AI B-ai_tec
-enabled O
capabilities O
and O
effectively O
experiment O
with O
new O
operating O
concepts O
in O
support O
of O
DoD B-Org
's O
military O
missions O
and O
business O
functions. O
The O
JAIC B-Org
marks O
the O
second O
major O
initiative O
Pentagon B-Org
leaders O
handed O
over O
to O
Deasy B-Person
, O
a O
former O
CIO O
with O
JPMorgan B-Org
Chase I-Org
who O
has O
only O
been O
at O
the O
Pentagon B-Org
for O
a O
few O
weeks. O
Deasy B-Person
also O
is O
in O
charge O
of O
managing O
the O
department's O
JEDI B-ai_program
cloud O
computing O
contract. O
The O
idea O
of O
standing O
up O
an O
AI B-ai_tec
center O
was O
first O
confirmed O
by O
Secretary O
of O
Defense O
Jim B-Person
Mattis I-Person
on O
April B-Date
12 I-Date
, O
but O
it O
has O
been O
championed O
by O
the O
Defense B-Org
Innovation I-Org
Board I-Org
, O
a O
group O
of O
outside O
experts O
ho O
advice O
the O
secretary O
on O
potential O
updates O
to O
how O
the O
Pentagon B-Org
handles O
evolving O
technologies. O
According O
to O
Michael B-Person
Griffin I-Person
, O
the O
head O
of O
Pentagon B-Org
research O
and O
engineering, O
the O
department O
counts O
592 O
projects O
as O
having O
some O
form O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
in O
them. O
However, O
Griffin B-Person
said O
in O
April B-Date
18 I-Date
testimony O
that O
he O
did O
not O
believe O
every O
one O
of O
those O
projects O
makes O
sense O
to O
roll O
into O
some O
sort O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
hub. O
That O
concern O
appears O
to O
be O
reflected O
in O
Shanahan B-Person
's O
memo, O
which O
orders O
that O
any O
AI B-ai_tec
project O
with O
a O
budget O
of O
$15 O
million O
or O
more O
should O
be O
coordinated O
with O
the O
services O
in O
order O
to O
ensure O
" O
DoD B-Org
is O
creating O
Department-wide O
advantages." O
In O
terms O
of O
budget, O
Shanahan B-Person
ordered O
the O
Pentagon B-Org
's O
comptroller O
to O
find O
options O
for O
funding O
during O
the O
current O
fiscal O
year, O
but O
the O
major O
focus O
is O
on O
driving O
resources O
for O
fiscal O
year O
2019 B-Date
and O
beyond. O
Given O
the O
support O
for O
artificial B-ai_tec
intelligence I-ai_tec
research O
on O
the O
Hill, O
it O
is O
likely O
the O
final O
version O
of O
the O
National B-MISC
Defense I-MISC
Authorization I-MISC
Act I-MISC
for I-MISC
FY19 I-MISC
will O
include O
some O
funding O
for O
the O
new O
office. O
The O
movement O
of O
Project B-ai_program
Maven I-ai_program
to O
the O
JAIC B-Org
is O
notable. O
A O
DoD B-Org
initiative O
to O
accelerate O
the O
integration O
of O
big B-ai_tec
data I-ai_tec
and O
machine B-ai_tec
learning I-ai_tec
, O
largely O
drawing O
on O
video O
feeds O
from O
unmanned B-ai_product
systems I-ai_product
, O
Maven B-ai_program
in O
the O
last O
month O
has O
become O
a O
poster O
child O
for O
the O
clash O
of O
cultures O
between O
the O
defense O
department O
and O
Silicon B-Org
Valley I-Org
. O
Google B-Org
was O
working O
hand-in-hand O
with O
the O
Pentagon B-Org
on O
the O
project, O
until O
a O
backlash O
from O
the O
company's O
employees, O
who O
argued O
in O
an O
open O
letter O
signed O
by O
more O
than O
3,000 O
workers O
that O
it O
did O
not O
want O
to O
"build O
warfare O
technology." O
Moving O
the O
program O
to O
the O
JAIC B-Org
may O
be O
an O
attempt O
to O
keep O
the O
project O
underway O
without O
Google B-Org
's O
participation. O

