U.S. B-Gpe
Special B-Org
Operations I-Org
Command I-Org
is O
ramping O
up O
its O
efforts O
to O
develop O
" O
cutting-edge B-ai_program
data I-ai_program
techniques I-ai_program
" O
like O
artificial B-ai_tec
intelligence I-ai_tec
to O
boost O
readiness O
and O
minimize O
costs. O
As O
part O
of O
that O
initiative, O
the O
command O
unveiled O
its O
new O
Data B-MISC
Engineering I-MISC
Lab I-MISC
located O
at O
the O
SOFWERX B-Org
facility O
in O
Tampa B-Gpe
, O
Florida B-Gpe
, O
on O
Wednesday B-Date
. O
SOFWERX B-Org
was O
established O
under O
a O
partnership O
intermediary O
agreement O
with O
SOCOM B-Org
and O
DEFENSEWERX B-Org
, O
formerly O
known O
as O
the O
Doolittle B-Org
Institute I-Org
, O
to O
help O
address O
war O
fighter O
problems O
for O
the O
command. O
The O
lab O
was O
designed O
to O
cultivate O
AI B-ai_tec
, O
machine B-ai_tec
learning I-ai_tec
, O
and O
robotic B-ai_tec
process I-ai_tec
automation I-ai_tec
— O
all O
to O
boost O
the O
performance O
and O
strength O
of O
special O
operations O
forces, O
SOCOM B-Org
spokeswoman O
Army O
Maj. O
Jennifer B-Person
Bocanegra I-Person
told O
the O
Military B-MISC
Times I-MISC
. O
"The O
DEL B-ai_product
is O
modeled O
off O
of O
leading O
technology O
companies, O
where O
DoD B-Org
partners, O
industry O
thought O
leaders, O
academia O
and O
Special B-MISC
Operations I-MISC
Forces I-MISC
collaborate O
to O
develop, O
test O
and O
employ O
new O
technical O
approaches O
to O
modernize O
warfighting O
decision O
making," O
Bocanegra B-Person
said O
in O
an O
email O
to O
the O
Military B-MISC
Times I-MISC
. O
Already, O
several O
projects O
are O
underway O
at O
the O
DEL B-ai_product
, O
according O
to O
Bocanegra B-Person
. O
Along O
with O
the O
Pentagon B-MISC
's O
Joint B-Org
Artificial I-Org
Intelligence I-Org
Center I-Org
, O
the O
DEL B-ai_product
is O
working O
on O
a O
project O
supporting O
the O
160th O
Special B-MISC
Operations I-MISC
Aviation I-MISC
Regiment I-MISC
based O
at O
Fort B-MISC
Campbell I-MISC
in O
Kentucky B-Gpe
to O
use O
AI B-ai_tec
and O
machine B-ai_tec
learning I-ai_tec
technology O
to O
help O
predict O
and O
prevent O
key O
mechanical O
issues, O
and O
to O
enhance O
the O
effectiveness O
of O
aircraft O
maintenance, O
among O
other O
things. O
"This O
project O
is O
in O
its O
early O
stages, O
but O
initial O
data O
collection, O
analysis O
and O
use O
of O
results O
have O
resulted O
in O
a O
significant O
increase O
in O
readiness, O
at O
cost O
savings," O
Bocanegra B-Person
said. O
A O
ribbon O
cutting O
ceremony O
for O
the O
opening O
of O
the O
lab O
was O
held O
on O
Wednesday B-Date
, O
and O
included O
remarks O
from O
SOCOM B-Org
commander, O
Army O
Gen. O
Richard B-Person
Clarke I-Person
and O
SOCOM B-Org
Chief O
Data O
Officer O
David O
Spirk. O
SOCOM B-Org
's O
Data B-MISC
Engineering I-MISC
Lab I-MISC
grand O
opening O
took O
place O
in O
Ybor B-Gpe
City I-Gpe
in O
Tampa B-Gpe
yesterday. O
The O
DEL B-ai_product
is O
specifically O
designed O
to O
develop O
and O
leverage O
cutting O
edge O
data O
techniques, O
including O
AI B-ai_tec
& O
machine B-ai_tec
learning I-ai_tec
, O
to O
enhance O
SOF B-MISC
effectiveness O
and O
capabilities... O
Spirk B-Org
joined O
SOCOM B-Org
in O
2018 B-Date
, O
after O
working O
with O
the O
Department B-Org
of I-Org
Defense I-Org
's O
Project B-ai_program
Maven I-ai_program
Program O
that O
launched O
in O
April B-Date
2017 I-Date
. O
The O
artificial B-ai_tec
intelligence I-ai_tec
program O
is O
designed O
to O
use O
machine B-ai_tec
learning I-ai_tec
and O
artificial B-ai_tec
intelligence I-ai_tec
to O
process O
full-motion O
video. O
The O
new O
lab O
comes O
as O
SOCOM B-Org
is O
composing O
a O
new O
artificial B-ai_tec
intelligence I-ai_tec
and O
machine B-ai_tec
learning I-ai_tec
strategy O
as O
part O
of O
its O
program O
objective O
memorandum O
for O
fiscal O
years O
2022 B-Date
to I-Date
2026 I-Date
. O
At O
the O
time, O
Spirk B-Org
said O
Special B-MISC
Operations I-MISC
Forces I-MISC
components O
would O
start O
crafting O
the O
strategy O
starting O
in O
September B-Date
. O
"We're O
going O
to O
start O
the O
crafting O
of O
a O
real O
roadmap," O
he O
said O
at O
the O
Special B-MISC
Operations I-MISC
Forces I-MISC
Industry I-MISC
Conference I-MISC
in O
May B-Date
, O
according O
to O
National B-Org
Defense I-Org
. O
"This O
will O
help O
the O
command...talk O
about O
the O
investments O
we O
need O
to O
make O
and O
the O
resources O
that O
we're O
going O
to O
need."The O
DEL B-ai_product
will O
be O
overseen O
by O
SOCOM B-Org
's O
Data O
Office, O
but O
will O
be O
housed O
in O
SOFWERX B-Org
's O
facility O
in O
Tampa B-Gpe
's O
Ybor B-Gpe
City I-Gpe
. O
SOFWERX B-Org
and O
the O
new O
data O
lab O
will O
both O
address O
solutions O
for O
special O
operator O
needs, O
Bocanegra B-Person
said. O
"Being O
co-located O
provides O
opportunities O
for O
the O
DEL B-ai_product
and O
SOFWERX B-Org
to O
collaborate O
on O
future O
challenges O
for O
the O
Special B-MISC
Operations I-MISC
community I-MISC
," O
Bocanegra B-Person
said. O

