The O
military B-Org
has O
its O
eye O
on O
artificial B-ai_tec
intelligence I-ai_tec
solutions O
to O
everything O
from O
data O
analysis O
to O
surveillance, O
maintenance O
and O
medical O
care, O
but O
before O
the O
Defense B-Org
Department I-Org
moves O
full O
steam O
ahead O
into O
an O
AI B-ai_tec
future, O
they're O
laying O
out O
some O
ethical O
principles O
to O
live O
by. O
Defense O
Secretary O
Mark B-Person
Esper I-Person
signed O
off O
on O
five O
guidelines O
in O
a O
memo O
released O
Monday, O
" O
The B-Gpe
United I-Gpe
States I-Gpe
, O
together O
with O
our O
allies O
and O
partners, O
must O
accelerate O
the O
adoption O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
and O
lead O
in O
its O
national O
security O
applications O
to O
maintain O
our O
strategic O
position, O
prevail O
on O
future O
battlefields, O
and O
safeguard O
the O
rules-based O
international O
order," O
said O
Esper B-Person
wrote. O
" O
AI B-ai_tec
technology O
will O
change O
much O
about O
the O
battlefield O
of O
the O
future, O
but O
nothing O
will O
change O
America B-Gpe
's O
steadfast O
commitment O
to O
responsible O
and O
lawful O
behavior." O
The O
list O
is O
the O
result O
of O
a O
15-month O
study O
by O
the O
Defense B-Org
Innovation I-Org
Board I-Org
, O
which O
is O
made O
up O
of O
academics O
and O
executives O
in O
tech O
and O
business, O
who O
presented O
their O
proposed O
principles O
in O
a O
public O
forum O
at O
Georgetown B-Org
University I-Org
in O
October B-Date
. O
According O
to O
Esper B-Person
's O
Monday O
memo, O
the O
Pentagon B-Org
pledges O
that O
its O
AI B-ai_tec
efforts O
will O
be: O
1) O
Responsible, O
2) O
Equitable, O
3) O
Traceable, O
4) O
Reliable O
and O
5) O
Governable. O
In O
short, O
any O
technology's O
development O
and O
operation O
should O
be O
carefully O
developed O
and O
used, O
have O
safeguards O
against O
bias O
in O
data O
analysis, O
be O
auditable O
to O
find O
the O
sources O
of O
mistakes O
and O
correct O
them, O
have O
narrowly-defined O
parameters O
for O
use O
and O
have O
back-up O
plans O
for O
shut O
down O
in O
case O
something O
goes O
wrong. O
"We O
owe O
it O
to O
the O
America B-Gpe
n O
people O
and O
our O
men O
and O
women O
in O
uniform O
to O
adopt O
AI B-ai_tec
principles O
that O
reflect O
our O
nation's O
values O
of O
a O
free O
and O
open O
society," O
Lt. O
Gen. O
Jack B-Person
Shanahan I-Person
, O
head O
of O
the O
Joint B-Org
Artificial I-Org
Intelligence I-Org
Center I-Org
, O
told O
reporters O
Monday. O
"This O
runs O
in O
stark O
contrast O
to O
Russia B-Gpe
and O
China B-Gpe
, O
whose O
use O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
tech O
for O
military O
purposes O
raises O
serious O
concern O
about O
human O
rights, O
ethics O
and O
international O
norms." O
China B-Gpe
, O
for O
example, O
has O
used O
its O
facial O
recognition O
AI B-ai_tec
technology O
to O
surveil O
its O
citizens' O
public O
activity. O
"I O
do O
not O
believe O
… O
that O
China B-Gpe
or O
Russia B-Gpe
are O
having O
any O
sort O
of O
conversation O
like O
we're O
having O
today," O
Shanahan B-Person
said, O
taking O
questions O
from O
the O
press O
in O
a O
public O
broadcast. O
The B-Org
White I-Org
House I-Org
is O
scheduled O
to O
release O
its O
own O
set O
of O
principles O
this O
summer, O
he O
said. O
"Our O
intentions O
are O
clear: O
We O
will O
do O
what O
it O
takes O
to O
ensure O
that O
the O
U.S. B-Org
military I-Org
lives O
up O
to O
our O
nation's O
ethical O
values O
while O
maintaining O
and O
strengthening O
America B-Gpe
's O
technological O
advantage," O
Shanahan B-Person
said. O
DoD B-Org
is O
at O
the O
"ground O
floor" O
of O
its O
AI B-ai_tec
journey, O
according O
to O
Shanahan B-Person
, O
so O
there O
are O
few O
concrete O
examples O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
technology O
that O
will O
be O
subject O
to O
these O
principles. O
The O
JAIC B-Org
, O
his O
organization, O
has O
been O
working O
developing O
a O
tool O
for O
UH-60 B-MISC
Black I-MISC
Hawk I-MISC
helicopter I-MISC
maintenance, O
he O
said, O
as O
well O
as O
some O
cyber O
defense O
technology O
and O
solutions O
to O
make O
military O
health O
care O
more O
efficient. O
One O
past O
project, O
dubbed O
Maven B-ai_program
, O
made O
headlines O
in O
2018 B-Date
, O
when O
Gizmodo B-Org
reported O
that O
Google B-Org
had O
been O
quietly O
allowing O
DoD B-Org
access O
to O
a O
software O
program O
that O
could O
use O
AI B-ai_tec
to O
recognize O
objects O
in O
drone O
footage. O
Some O
Google B-Org
employees O
were O
dismayed O
to O
find O
that O
their O
employer O
was O
potentially O
helping O
the O
military O
home O
in O
on O
human O
targets. O
"We O
would O
be O
doing O
these O
AI B-ai_tec
ethics O
principles O
regardless O
of O
the O
angst O
in O
the O
tech O
industry," O
Shanahan B-Person
said. O
"And O
sometimes O
I O
think O
the O
angst O
is O
a O
little O
hyped, O
but O
we O
do O
have O
people O
who O
have O
serious O
concerns O
about O
working O
with O
the O
Department B-Org
of I-Org
Defense I-Org
." O
In O
hindsight, O
he O
said, O
secretly O
launching O
Project B-ai_program
Maven I-ai_program
would O
not O
line O
up O
with O
the O
new O
ethics O
principles. O
"If O
we O
would O
have O
had O
the O
AI B-ai_tec
ethics O
principles O
three O
years O
ago O
… O
and O
our O
starting O
point O
with O
one O
of O
the O
big O
tech O
companies O
was O
that O
— O
and O
we O
were O
transparent O
about O
what O
we O
were O
trying O
to O
do O
and O
why O
we O
were O
trying O
to O
do O
it O
— O
maybe O
we O
would O
have O
had O
a O
different O
outcome," O
he O
said. O

