All O
U.S. B-Gpe
military O
services O
are O
working O
to O
incorporate O
AI B-ai_tec
into O
semiautonomous B-ai_product
and I-ai_product
autonomous I-ai_product
vehicles I-ai_product
, O
including O
fighter O
aircraft, O
drones B-ai_product
, O
ground O
vehicles, O
and O
naval O
vessels. O
AI B-ai_product
applications I-ai_product
in O
this O
field O
are O
similar O
to O
those O
for O
commercial O
semiautonomous B-ai_product
vehicles I-ai_product
, O
which O
use O
AI B-ai_tec
technologies O
to O
perceive O
the O
environment, O
recognize O
obstacles, O
fuse O
sensor O
data, O
plan O
navigation, O
and O
even O
communicate O
with O
other O
vehicles. O
The O
Air B-Org
Force I-Org
Research I-Org
Lab I-Org
completed O
phase-two O
tests O
of O
its O
Loyal B-ai_program
Wingman I-ai_program
program, O
which O
pairs O
an O
older-generation, O
uninhabited O
fighter O
jet O
(in O
this O
case, O
an O
F-16) O
with O
an O
inhabited O
F-35 O
or O
F-22. O
During O
this O
event, O
the O
uninhabited O
F-16 O
test O
platform O
autonoously O
reacted O
to O
events O
that O
were O
not O
preprogrammed, O
such O
as O
weather O
and O
unforeseen O
obstacles. O
As O
the O
program O
progresses, O
AI B-ai_tec
may O
enable O
the O
“loyal O
wingman” O
to O
accomplish O
tasks O
for O
its O
inhabited O
flight O
lead, O
such O
as O
jamming O
electronic O
threats O
or O
carrying O
extra O
weapons. O
The O
Army B-Org
and O
the O
Marine B-Org
Corps I-Org
tested O
prototypes O
of O
similar O
vehicles O
that O
follow O
soldiers O
or O
vehicles O
around O
the O
battlefield O
to O
accomplish O
independent O
tasks. O
For O
example, O
the O
Marine B-Org
Corps I-Org
’ O
Multi-Utility O
Tactical O
Transport O
(MUTT) O
is O
a O
remote-controlled, O
ATV-sized O
vehicle O
capable O
of O
carrying O
hundreds O
of O
pounds O
of O
extra O
equipment. O
Although O
the O
system O
is O
not O
autonomous O
in O
its O
current O
configuration, O
the O
Marine B-Org
Corps I-Org
intends O
for O
follow-on O
systems O
to O
have O
greater O
independence. O
Likewise, O
the O
Army B-Org
plans O
to O
field O
a O
number O
of O
Robotic B-ai_product
Combat I-ai_product
Vehicles I-ai_product
( O
RCVs B-ai_product
) O
with O
different O
types O
of O
autonomous O
functionality, O
including O
navigation, O
surveillance, O
and O
IED O
removal. O
These O
systems O
will O
be O
deployed O
as O
“wingmen” O
for O
the O
optionally O
inhabited O
Next O
Generation O
Ground O
Vehicle, O
tentatively O
scheduled O
for O
initial O
soldier O
evaluations O
in O
FY2020 B-Date
. O
DARPA B-Org
completed O
testing O
of O
the O
Anti-Submarine B-ai_product
Warfare I-ai_product
Continuous I-ai_product
Trail I-ai_product
Unmanned I-ai_product
Vessel I-ai_product
prototype, O
or O
“ O
Sea B-ai_product
Hunter I-ai_product
,” O
in O
early B-Date
2018 I-Date
before O
transitioning O
program O
development O
to O
the O
Office B-Org
of I-Org
Naval I-Org
Research I-Org
. O
If O
Sea O
Hunter O
enters O
into O
service, O
it O
would O
provide O
the O
Navy B-Org
with O
the O
ability O
to O
autonomously O
navigate O
the O
open O
seas, O
swap O
out O
modular O
payloads, O
and O
coordinate O
missions O
with O
other O
unmanned B-ai_product
vessels I-ai_product
—all O
while O
providing O
continuous O
submarine-hunting O
coverage O
for O
months O
at O
a O
time. O
Some O
analysts O
estimate O
that O
Sea O
Hunter O
would O
cost O
around O
$20,000 O
a O
day O
to O
operate, O
in O
contrast O
to O
around O
$700,000 O
for O
a O
traditionally O
inhabited O
destroyer. O
DOD B-Org
is O
testing O
other O
AI-fueled B-ai_tec
capabilities O
to O
enable O
cooperative O
behavior, O
or O
swarming. O
Swarming O
is O
a O
unique O
subset O
of O
autonomous B-ai_product
vehicle I-ai_product
development, O
with O
concepts O
ranging O
from O
large O
formations O
of O
low-cost O
vehicles O
designed O
to O
overwhelm O
defensive O
systems O
to O
small O
squadrons O
of O
vehicles O
that O
collaborate O
to O
provide O
electronic O
attack, O
fire O
support, O
and O
localized O
navigation O
and O
communication O
nets O
for O
ground-troop O
formations. O
A O
number O
of O
different O
swarm O
capabilities O
are O
currently O
under O
development. O
For O
example, O
in O
November B-Date
2016 I-Date
, O
the O
Navy B-Org
completed O
a O
test O
of O
an O
AI-enabled B-ai_tec
swarm O
of O
five O
unmanned B-ai_product
boats I-ai_product
that O
cooperatively O
patrolled O
a O
4-by-4-mile O
section O
of O
the O
Chesapeake B-Loc
Bay I-Loc
and O
intercepted O
an O
“intruder” O
vessel. O
The O
results O
of O
this O
experiment O
may O
lead O
to O
AI B-ai_tec
technology O
adapted O
for O
defending O
harbors, O
hunting O
submarines, O
or O
scouting O
in O
front O
of O
a O
formation O
of O
larger O
ships. O
The O
Navy B-Org
also O
plans O
to O
test O
swarms O
of O
underwater B-ai_product
drones I-ai_product
, O
and O
the O
Strategic B-Org
Capabilities I-Org
Office I-Org
has O
successfully O
tested O
a O
swarm O
of O
103 O
air-dropped O
micro-drones B-ai_product
. O
Lethal B-ai_product
Autonomous I-ai_product
Weapon I-ai_product
Systems I-ai_product
( O
LAWS B-ai_product
) O
are O
a O
special O
class O
of O
weapon O
systems O
that O
use O
sensor O
suites O
and O
computer O
algorithms O
to O
independently O
identify O
a O
target O
and O
employ O
an O
onboard O
weapon O
system O
to O
engage O
and O
destroy O
the O
target O
without O
manual O
human O
control O
of O
the O
system. O
Although O
these O
systems O
generally O
do O
not O
yet O
exist, O
it O
is O
believed O
they O
would O
enable O
military O
operations O
in O
communications-degraded O
or O
-denied O
environments O
in O
which O
traditional O
systems O
may O
not O
be O
able O
to O
operate. O
The O
U.S. B-Gpe
military O
does O
not O
currently O
have O
LAWS B-ai_product
in O
its O
inventory, O
although O
there O
are O
no O
legal O
prohibitions O
on O
the O
development O
of O
LAWS B-ai_product
. O
DOD B-Org
Directive B-ai_program
3000.09 I-ai_program
, O
“ O
Autonomy B-ai_tec
in O
Weapon O
Systems,” O
outlines O
department O
policies O
for O
semiautonomous B-ai_product
and I-ai_product
autonomous I-ai_product
weapon I-ai_product
systems I-ai_product
. O
The O
directive O
requires O
that O
all O
systems, O
regardless O
of O
classification, O
be O
designed O
to O
“allow O
commanders O
and O
operators O
to O
exercise O
appropriate O
levels O
of O
human O
judgment O
over O
the O
use O
of O
force” O
and O
to O
successfully O
complete O
the O
department’s O
weapons O
review O
process. O
Any O
changes O
to O
the O
system’s O
operating O
state O
require O
that O
the O
system O
go O
through O
the O
weapons O
review O
process O
again O
to O
ensure O
that O
it O
has O
retained O
the O
ability O
to O
operate O
as O
intended. O
Autonomous B-ai_product
weapons I-ai_product
and O
a O
limited O
type O
of O
semiautonomous B-ai_product
weapons I-ai_product
must O
additionally O
be O
approved O
before O
both O
development O
and O
fielding O
by O
the O
Under O
Secretary O
of O
Defense O
for O
Policy, O
the O
Chairman O
of O
the O
Joint B-Org
Chiefs I-Org
of I-Org
Staff I-Org
, O
and O
either O
the O
Under O
Secretary O
of O
Defense O
for O
Acquisition O
and O
Sustainment O
or O
the O
Under O
Secretary O
of O
Defense O
for O
Research O
and O
Engineering. O
Human-supervised O
autonomous B-ai_product
weapons I-ai_product
used O
for O
point O
defense O
of O
manned O
installations O
or O
platforms—but O
that O
do O
not O
target O
humans—and O
autonomous O
weapons O
that O
“apply O
non-lethal, O
non-kinetic O
force, O
such O
as O
some O
forms O
of O
electronic O
attack, O
against O
materiel O
targets” O
are O
exempted O
from O
this O
senior-level O
review. O
Despite O
this O
policy, O
some O
senior O
military O
and O
defense O
leaders O
have O
expressed O
concerns O
about O
the O
prospect O
of O
fielding O
LAWS B-ai_product
. O
For O
example, O
in O
2017 B-Date
testimony O
before O
the O
Senate B-Org
Armed I-Org
Services I-Org
Committee I-Org
, O
then-Vice O
Chairman O
of O
the O
Joint B-Org
Chiefs I-Org
of I-Org
Staff I-Org
General O
Paul B-Person
Selva I-Person
stated, O
“I O
do O
not O
think O
it O
is O
reasonable O
for O
us O
to O
put O
robots O
in O
charge O
of O
whether O
or O
not O
we O
take O
a O
human O
life.” O
Regardless, O
General O
Selva B-Person
explained O
that O
the O
military O
will O
be O
compelled O
to O
address O
the O
development O
of O
this O
class O
of O
technology O
in O
order O
to O
find O
its O
vulnerabilities, O
given O
the O
fact O
that O
potential O
U.S. B-Gpe
adversaries O
are O
pursuing O
LAWS B-ai_product
. O
Indeed, O
as O
Secretary O
of O
Defense O
Mark B-Person
Esper I-Person
has O
noted, O
“Chinese O
weapons O
manufacturers O
are O
selling O
drones B-ai_product
advertised O
as O
capable O
of O
full O
autonomy B-ai_tec
, O
including O
the O
ability O
to O
conduct O
lethal O
targeted O
strikes” O

