Some O
reports O
indicate O
that O
DOD B-Org
and O
the O
defense O
industry O
also O
face O
challenges O
when O
it O
comes O
to O
recruiting O
and O
retaining O
personnel O
with O
expertise O
in O
AI B-ai_tec
due O
to O
research O
funding O
and O
salaries O
that O
significantly O
lag O
behind O
those O
of O
commercial O
companies. O
Other O
reports O
suggest O
that O
such O
challenges O
stem O
from O
quality-of-life O
factors, O
as O
well O
as O
from O
a O
belief O
among O
many O
technology O
workers O
that O
“they O
can O
achieve O
large-scale O
change O
faster O
and O
better O
outside O
the O
government O
than O
within O
it.” O
This O
sentiment O
echoes O
the O
findings O
of O
the O
National B-Org
Security I-Org
Commission I-Org
on I-Org
Artificial I-Org
Intelligence I-Org
, O
which O
notes O
that O
“ O
AI B-ai_tec
experts O
would O
be O
willing O
to O
serve O
in O
government O
if O
officials O
could O
create O
a O
more O
compelling O
sense O
of O
purpose O
and O
a O
technical O
environment O
within O
government O
that O
would O
maximize O
their O
talents.” O
Regardless, O
observers O
note O
that O
if O
DOD B-Org
and O
defense O
industry O
are O
unable O
to O
recruit O
and O
retain O
the O
appropriate O
experts, O
military O
AI B-ai_product
applications I-ai_product
could O
be O
delayed, O
“deficient, O
or O
lacking O
in O
appropriate O
safeguards O
and O
testing.” O
To O
address O
these O
challenges, O
the O
Obama B-Org
Administration I-Org
launched O
the O
Defense B-ai_program
Digital I-ai_program
Service I-ai_program
in O
2015 B-Date
as O
a O
means O
of O
recruiting O
private O
sector O
technology O
workers O
to O
serve O
in O
DOD B-Org
for O
one O
to O
two O
year O
assignments—a O
“tour O
of O
duty O
for O
nerds,” O
according O
to O
former O
director O
Chris B-Person
Lynch I-Person
. O
Similarly, O
former O
Deputy O
Secretary O
of O
Defense B-Org
Bob B-Person
Work I-Person
has O
proposed O
an O
“ O
AI B-ai_program
Training I-ai_program
Corps I-ai_program
,” O
in O
which O
DOD B-Org
“would O
pay O
for O
advanced O
technical O
education O
in O
exchange O
for O
two B-Date
days I-Date
a I-Date
month I-Date
of O
training O
with O
government O
systems O
and O
two B-Date
weeks I-Date
a I-Date
year I-Date
for O
major O
exercises.” O
Participants O
in O
the O
program O
could O
additionally O
be O
called O
to O
government O
service O
in O
the O
event O
of O
a O
national O
emergency. O
Other O
analysts O
have O
recommended O
the O
establishment O
of O
new O
military O
training O
and O
occupational O
specialties O
to O
cultivate O
AI B-ai_tec
talent, O
as O
well O
as O
the O
creation O
of O
government O
fellowships O
and O
accelerated O
promotion O
tracks O
to O
reward O
the O
most O
talented O
technology O
workers. O
An O
apparent O
cultural O
divide O
between O
DOD B-Org
and O
commercial O
technology O
companies O
may O
also O
present O
challenges O
for O
AI B-ai_tec
adoption. O
A O
recent O
survey O
of O
leadership O
in O
several O
top O
Silicon B-Loc
Valley I-Loc
companies O
found O
that O
nearly O
80% O
of O
participants O
rated O
the O
commercial O
technology O
community’s O
relationship O
with O
DOD B-Org
as O
poor O
or O
very O
poor. O
This O
was O
due O
to O
a O
number O
of O
factors, O
including O
process O
challenges, O
perceptions O
of O
mutual O
distrust, O
and O
differences O
between O
DOD B-Org
and O
commercial O
incentive O
structures. O
Moreover, O
some O
companies O
are O
refusing O
to O
work O
with O
DOD B-Org
due O
to O
ethical O
concerns O
over O
the O
government’s O
use O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
in O
surveillance O
or O
weapon O
systems. O
Notably, O
Google B-Org
canceled O
existing O
government O
contracts O
for O
two O
robotics O
companies O
it O
acquired— O
Boston B-Org
Dynamics I-Org
and O
Schaft B-Org
— O
and O
prohibited O
future O
government O
work O
for O
DeepMind B-Org
, O
a O
Google B-Org
-acquired O
AI B-ai_tec
software O
startup. O
In O
May B-Date
2018 I-Date
, O
Google B-Org
employees O
successfully O
lobbied O
the O
company O
to O
withdraw O
from O
Project B-ai_program
Maven I-ai_program
and O
refrain O
from O
further O
collaboration O
with O
DOD B-Org
. O
Other O
companies, O
however, O
have O
pledged O
to O
continue O
supporting O
DOD B-Org
contracts, O
with O
Amazon B-Org
CEO O
Jeff B-Person
Bezos I-Person
noting O
that O
“if O
big O
tech O
companies O
are O
going O
to O
turn O
their O
back O
on O
the O
U.S. B-Gpe
Department B-Org
of I-Org
Defense I-Org
, O
this O
country O
is O
going O
to O
be O
in O
trouble.” O
Cultural O
factors O
within O
the O
defense O
establishment O
itself O
may O
also O
impede O
AI B-ai_tec
integration. O
The O
integration O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
into O
existing O
systems O
alters O
standardized O
procedures O
and O
upends O
well-defined O
personnel O
roles. O
Members O
of O
Project B-ai_program
Maven I-ai_program
have O
reported O
a O
resistance O
to O
AI B-ai_tec
integration O
because O
integration O
can O
be O
disruptive O
without O
always O
providing O
an O
immediately O
recognizable O
benefit. O
Deputy O
Director O
for O
CIA B-Org
technology O
development O
Dawn B-Person
Meyerriecks I-Person
has O
also O
expressed O
concern O
about O
the O
willingness O
of O
senior O
leaders O
to O
accept O
AI-generated B-ai_tec
analysis, O
arguing O
that O
the O
defense O
establishment’s O
risk-averse O
culture O
may O
pose O
greater O
challenges O
to O
future O
competitiveness O
than O
the O
pace O
of O
adversary O
technology O
development. O
Finally, O
some O
analysts O
are O
concerned O
that O
DOD B-Org
will O
not O
capitalize O
on O
AI B-ai_tec
’s O
potential O
to O
produce O
game-changing O
warfighting O
benefits O
and O
will O
instead O
simply O
use O
AI B-ai_tec
to O
incrementally O
improve O
existing O
processes O
or O
reinforce O
current O
operational O
concepts. O
Furthermore, O
the O
services O
may O
reject O
certain O
AI B-ai_product
applications I-ai_product
altogether O
if O
the O
technology O
threatens O
service-favored O
hardware O
or O
missions. O
Members O
of O
Congress B-Org
may O
explore O
the O
complex O
interaction O
of O
these O
factors O
as O
DOD B-Org
moves O
beyond O
the O
initial O
stages O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
adoption. O

