WASHINGTON B-Gpe
: O
When O
former O
Deputy O
Defense O
Secretary O
Bob B-Person
Work I-Person
heard O
the O
head O
of O
Google B-Org
's O
parent O
company, O
Eric B-Person
Schmidt I-Person
, O
say O
this O
morning O
that O
America B-Gpe
needs O
a O
national O
strategy O
for O
developing O
Artificial B-ai_tec
Intelligence I-ai_tec
, O
one O
image O
sprang O
to O
his O
mind's O
eye. O
"The O
image O
that O
popped O
into O
my O
mind O
was O
of O
Nikita B-Person
Khrushchev I-Person
banging O
his O
shoe O
in O
the O
UN B-Org
and O
saying, O
'We O
will O
bury O
you," O
Work B-Person
said. O
Work B-Person
told O
me O
Schmidt B-Person
was O
"absolutely O
right" O
to O
call O
for O
America B-Gpe
to O
come O
up O
with O
its O
own O
strategic O
plan O
to O
boost O
its O
work O
on O
AI B-ai_tec
, O
as O
China B-Gpe
recently O
did. O
"As O
Eric B-Person
said, O
the O
US B-Gpe
does O
not O
have O
a O
coherent O
strategy" O
for O
developing O
AI B-ai_tec
, O
said O
Work B-Person
, O
father O
of O
the O
Pentagon B-Org
's O
Third B-MISC
Offset I-MISC
Strategy I-MISC
. O
China B-Gpe
's O
just O
announced O
an O
AI B-ai_tec
strategy O
designed O
to O
assure O
it O
will O
be O
dominant O
in O
the O
host O
of O
technologies O
by O
2030 B-Date
. O
"If O
you O
believe O
this O
is O
important, O
as O
I O
believe, O
then O
we O
need O
to O
get O
our O
act O
together O
as O
a O
country," O
Schmidt B-Person
said O
this O
morning. O
In O
a O
Q O
and O
A O
session O
at O
the O
event O
organized O
by O
the O
Center B-Org
for I-Org
a I-Org
New I-Org
American I-Org
Security I-Org
, O
Schmidt B-Person
said O
he O
thought O
the O
US B-Gpe
will O
maintain O
its O
lead O
over O
the O
People's B-Gpe
Republic I-Gpe
of I-Gpe
China I-Gpe
for O
the O
next O
five O
years, O
but O
he O
expects O
China B-Gpe
to O
catch O
up O
about O
then O
and O
pass O
us O
"extremely O
quickly." O
How O
important O
does O
China B-Gpe
think O
AI B-ai_tec
can O
be? O
Work B-Person
told O
me O
the O
Chinese B-Gpe
estimate O
they O
can O
boost O
economic O
growth O
with O
AI B-ai_tec
by O
26 O
percent O
by O
2030 B-Date
. O
"It's O
quite O
stunning," O
Work B-Person
said. O
And, O
of O
course, O
the O
PRC's B-Org
government I-Org
has O
published O
a O
national O
strategy O
and O
released O
it O
to O
the O
world. O
What's O
the O
best O
response O
by O
the O
United B-Gpe
States I-Gpe
, O
I O
asked O
Work B-Person
after O
Schmidt B-Person
spoke. O
The O
federal O
government O
needs O
to O
answer O
this O
question O
at O
its O
highest O
levels, O
as O
happened O
after O
the O
Soviet B-Gpe
Union I-Gpe
stunned O
the O
world O
and O
launched O
the O
first O
satellite, O
Sputnik B-MISC
, O
Work B-Person
said. O
This O
is O
not O
something O
the O
Pentagon B-Org
can O
fix O
by O
itself. O
The O
US B-Gpe
should, O
at O
least, O
offer O
a O
free O
education O
"a O
free O
ride" O
to O
promising O
AI B-ai_tec
students, O
the O
former O
deputy O
defense O
secretary O
said. O
In O
return, O
they O
would O
agree O
to O
serve O
in O
an O
AI B-ai_tec
reserve O
corps, O
something O
like O
a O
cross O
between O
the O
Reserves B-Org
and O
National B-Org
Guard I-Org
. O
They O
could O
work O
for O
Alphabet B-Org
, O
Facebook B-Org
or O
any O
other O
company O
and O
make O
lots O
of O
money O
while O
also O
providing O
their O
unique O
skills O
to O
their O
country. O
A O
colleague O
and O
I O
pressed O
Work B-Person
, O
asking O
him O
if O
America B-Gpe
was O
likely O
to O
undertake O
such O
a O
major O
effort, O
barring O
a O
catalytic O
event O
that O
strikes O
fear O
into O
the O
voting O
public, O
as O
Sputnik B-MISC
did. O
His O
reply O
is O
worth O
noting: O
"If O
we O
wait O
for O
the O
Sputnik B-MISC
moment, O
we O
will O
be O
too O
far O
behind." O
In O
related O
news, O
Work B-Person
said O
he O
understands O
the O
Algorithmic B-Org
Warfare I-Org
Cross-Functional I-Org
Team I-Org
is O
on O
track O
to O
deploy O
its O
first O
algorithm O
by O
December B-Date
to O
sort O
through O
vast O
amounts O
of O
video O
collected O
by O
surveillance O
drones, O
a O
flood O
of O
data O
that's O
overwhelming O
human O
analysts. O
Schmidt B-Person
made O
the O
point O
during O
his O
remarks O
that O
the O
Defense B-Org
Department I-Org
wastes O
the O
talents O
of O
many O
of O
its O
highly O
trained O
personnel O
watching O
video O
screens O
and O
typing O
information O
from O
one O
system O
into O
another. O
That O
is O
exactly O
the O
sort O
of O
important, O
but O
mundane O
and O
mind-deadening O
work O
that O
AI B-ai_tec
s O
can O
take O
over O
from O
humans, O
Schmidt B-Person
said. O
Finally, O
Schmidt B-Person
, O
one O
of O
the O
few O
top O
software O
or O
social O
media O
executives O
to O
openly O
work O
with O
the O
Pentagon B-Org
as O
chairman O
of O
its O
Defense B-Org
Innovation I-Org
Advisory I-Org
Board I-Org
, O
also O
made O
the O
point O
that O
the O
United B-Gpe
States I-Gpe
risks O
much O
by O
excluding O
talented O
immigrants O
from O
the O
country. O
"Shockingly, O
some O
of O
the O
very O
best O
people O
are O
in O
countries O
where O
we O
won't O
them O
into O
America B-Gpe
." O
Iranians B-Gpe
, O
for O
example, O
are O
some O
of O
"the O
smartest O
and O
top O
computer O
scientists O
in O
the O
world," O
he O
said. O
He'd O
love O
to O
hire O
many O
of O
them, O
but O
Trump B-Person
administration O
policies O
make O
this O
extremely O
difficult. O
"It's O
crazy O
not O
to O
let O
them O
in," O
Schmidt B-Person
said. O
The O
president O
today O
slammed O
the O
immigration O
laws O
that O
allowed O
the O
coward O
in O
New B-Gpe
York I-Gpe
who O
killed O
people O
with O
his O
truck O
to O
enter O
the O
country. O
The O
person O
is O
from O
Uzbekistan B-Gpe
, O
which, O
of O
course, O
isn't O
on O
the O
administration's O
list O
of O
countries O
whose O
citizens O
were O
effectively O
barred O
from O
the O
US B-Gpe
by O
Trump's B-MISC
September I-MISC
executive I-MISC
order I-MISC
. O
(The O
judiciary O
has, O
so O
far, O
barred O
the O
administration O
from O
executing O
the O
order.) O
As O
a O
reminder, O
the O
order O
targets O
Iran B-Gpe
, O
Libya B-Gpe
, O
Syria B-Gpe
, O
Yemen B-Gpe
, O
Somalia B-Gpe
, O
Chad B-Gpe
and O
North B-Gpe
Korea I-Gpe
. O
Chad B-Gpe
, O
of O
course, O
had O
provided O
extensive O
help O
to O
the O
US B-Gpe
and O
allies O
in O
the O
fight O
against O
terrorism O
in O
Africa B-Gpe
. O
And O
who O
can O
count O
the O
number O
of O
North B-Gpe
Koreans I-Gpe
streaming O
into O
the O
United B-Gpe
States I-Gpe
? O

