"Generating O
a O
new O
workforce O
to O
execute O
these O
concepts O
is O
important, O
providing O
a O
conduit O
to O
the O
force O
with O
individuals O
in O
our O
formation O
having O
begun O
learning O
about O
AI B-ai_tec
and O
data O
science O
to O
actualize O
it," O
Spirk B-Person
said. O
He O
highlighted O
the O
critical O
nature O
of O
using O
special O
operations O
forces O
to O
identify O
"really O
creative O
ways O
to O
use O
technology O
which O
already O
exists O
today." O
"It's O
about O
understanding O
which O
computer O
capabilities O
won't O
take O
an O
algorithm O
and O
which O
workflows O
might O
benefit O
from O
AI B-ai_tec
," O
he O
added. O
As O
a O
result, O
Spirk B-Person
is O
overseeing O
a O
series O
of O
projects O
aligned O
against O
Clarke B-Person
's O
applied O
AI B-ai_tec
focus O
areas: O
"Perception O
and O
action," O
which O
will O
provide O
and O
receive O
support O
to O
and O
from O
Project B-ai_program
Maven I-ai_program
; O
"Planning O
and O
maneuver" O
opportunities O
that O
exploit O
commercial O
and O
academic O
wargaming O
techniques O
through O
the O
application O
of O
game O
theory; O
"Communications O
resilience O
and O
cyberwarfare B-MISC
" O
in O
order O
to O
protect O
the O
entire O
force; O
"Recruitment, O
training O
and O
talent O
management," O
which O
is O
focused O
on O
AI B-ai_tec
to O
aid O
the O
assessment O
and O
selection O
of O
special O
operators; O
"Business O
processes," O
which O
optimizes O
contract O
and O
budget O
management; O
and O
"Predictive O
maintenance O
and O
logistics," O
which O
will O
exploit O
data O
science O
to O
build O
algorithms O
for O
predicting O
engine O
failures O
and O
maintaining O
high O
readiness O
levels O
starting O
with O
rotary-wing O
aircraft. O
This O
last O
effort O
will O
involve O
Carnegie B-MISC
Mellon I-MISC
University I-MISC
and O
the O
Joint B-Org
Artificial I-Org
Intelligence I-Org
Center I-Org
. O
"We O
are O
talking O
about O
starting O
small O
with O
big O
intent. O
Take O
that O
bite, O
and O
once O
we O
show O
the O
art O
of O
the O
possible, O
stretch O
that O
win O
across O
the O
whole O
workflow," O
Spirk B-Person
said. O
In O
September B-Date
, O
SOCOM B-Org
will O
hold O
its O
inaugural O
AI B-ai_tec
symposium O
to O
create O
a O
road O
map O
to O
build O
a O
sustainable O
AI B-ai_tec
portfolio. O
"This O
is O
a O
huge O
opportunity O
to O
begin O
collecting O
operator O
responses O
while O
they're O
under O
the O
headset, O
and O
to O
take O
the O
last O
10 O
years O
of O
combat O
experience O
and O
make O
it O
structured, O
make O
it O
explicit O
to O
know O
exactly O
how O
operators O
are O
going O
to O
be O
acting O
in O
that O
environment," O
Spirk B-Person
said. O
To O
this O
end, O
the O
Command B-Org
Data I-Org
Office I-Org
will O
receive O
support O
from O
the O
forthcoming O
Data B-Org
Engineering I-Org
Laboratory I-Org
co-located O
with O
the O
SOFWERX B-Org
innovation O
in O
Ybor B-Gpe
City I-Gpe
, O
a O
neighborhood O
in O
Tampa B-Gpe
; O
as O
well O
as O
staffers O
from O
the O
JAIC B-Org
and O
the O
Defense B-Org
Digital I-Org
Service I-Org
. O
The O
symposium O
will O
also O
consider O
how O
machine O
learning O
and O
AI B-ai_tec
can O
support O
SOCOM B-Org
's O
component O
commands, O
as O
well O
as O
theater O
special O
operations O
commands, O
Spirk B-Person
said. O
"We O
will O
prioritize O
SOF B-MISC
activities O
and O
resources, O
and O
challenge O
inhibiting O
practices O
to O
aid O
the O
development O
of O
a O
data-driven O
force O
of O
the O
future O
with O
purpose-driven O
applications," O
he O
added. O
Spirk B-Person
reaffirmed O
Clarke B-Person
's O
priorities O
to O
compete O
and O
win O
for O
the O
nation, O
preserve O
and O
grow O
readiness, O
innovate O
for O
future O
threats, O
advance O
partnerships, O
and O
strengthen O
the O
force. O

