As O
the O
first-ever O
chief O
data O
officer O
at O
the O
U.S. B-Gpe
Special B-Org
Operations I-Org
Command I-Org
, O
or O
SOCOM B-Org
, O
David B-Person
Spirk I-Person
Jr. I-Person
is O
tasked O
with O
managing O
the O
high O
expectations O
of O
the O
Tampa B-Gpe
, O
Florida-based B-Gpe
organization. O
He O
is O
now O
celebrating O
his O
one-year O
anniversary O
on O
the O
job. O
In O
a O
May B-Date
speech, O
Gen. O
Richard B-Person
Clarke I-Person
Clarke I-Person
, O
the O
new O
head O
of O
SOCOM B-Org
, O
described O
how O
machine B-ai_tec
learning I-ai_tec
and O
AI B-ai_tec
can O
provide O
operators O
with O
tactical O
advantages O
by O
increasing O
situational O
awareness, O
reducing O
cognitive O
loads O
and O
improving O
the O
decision-making O
process. O
"There O
are O
new, O
innovative O
ways O
to O
bring O
this O
reality O
to O
the O
forefront," O
Spirk B-Person
told O
C4ISRNET. B-MISC
One O
of O
the O
most O
relevant O
SOCOM B-Org
programs O
that O
could O
significantly O
benefit O
from O
machine B-ai_tec
learning I-ai_tec
and O
AI B-ai_tec
is O
the O
Hyper B-ai_product
Enabled I-ai_product
Operator I-ai_product
concept I-ai_product
. O
HEO B-ai_product
replaces O
the O
five-year O
Tactical B-MISC
Assault I-MISC
Light I-MISC
Operator I-MISC
Suit I-MISC
effort. O
"The O
HEO B-ai_product
concept O
is O
one O
of O
the O
most O
important O
things O
SOCOM B-Org
can O
be O
doing O
right O
now," O
Spirk B-Person
said. O
"The O
only O
way O
we O
have O
HEO B-ai_product
in O
the O
future O
is O
if O
we O
can O
reduce O
the O
cognitive O
load O
of O
that O
operator O
and O
his O
ability O
to O
command O
his O
resources O
at O
his O
disposal O
through O
automation O
and O
applied O
AI B-ai_tec
." O
For O
example, O
machine B-ai_tec
learning I-ai_tec
and O
AI B-ai_tec
could O
help O
to O
process, O
exploit O
and O
disseminate O
data O
from O
intelligence, O
surveillance, O
and O
reconnaissance. O
Such O
an O
advantage O
could O
come O
in O
the O
form O
of O
new O
displays O
available O
to O
operators O
in O
the O
field. O
That O
technology O
could O
also O
improve O
automation O
at O
tactical O
operation O
centers, O
in O
turn O
providing O
special O
operations O
forces O
with O
mission-specific O
predictions, O
Spirk B-Person
noted. O
Before O
joining O
SOCOM B-Org
, O
Spirk B-Person
worked O
with O
the O
Department B-Org
of I-Org
Defense I-Org
's O
Project B-ai_program
Maven I-ai_program
program, O
which O
was O
started O
in O
April B-Date
2017 I-Date
to O
design O
computer-vision B-ai_tec
algorithms I-ai_tec
for O
the O
processing, O
exploitation O
and O
dissemination O
of O
full-motion O
video. O
The O
command O
is O
working O
to O
exploit O
machine B-ai_tec
learning I-ai_tec
and O
AI B-ai_tec
technologies O
across O
an O
increasingly O
complex O
operating O
environment, O
and O
Spirk B-Person
emphasized O
SOCOM B-Org
's O
mission O
to O
adhere O
to O
special O
operations O
forces' O
AI B-ai_tec
principles: O
grow O
the O
discipline, O
find O
a O
purpose-driven O
application O
and O
make O
it O
the O
norm. O
"Quick O
wins O
are O
demanded," O
Spirk B-Person
said. O
SOCOM B-Org
's O
Command B-Org
Data I-Org
Office I-Org
completed O
its O
first O
program O
review O
July B-Date
24 I-Date
— O
an O
event O
Clarke B-Person
attended. O
Previous O
leaders O
also O
gave O
him O
"explicit O
guidance O
to O
go O
faster O
and O
deeper O
while O
responsibly O
challenging O
legacy O
policies O
or O
processes O
that O
get O
in O
the O
way O
of O
our O
progress," O
Spirk B-Person
said. O
Such O
a O
strategy, O
he O
warned, O
is O
dependent O
upon O
cooperation O
across O
SOCOM B-Org
; O
the O
Command B-Org
Data I-Org
Office I-Org
in O
particular O
is O
tasked O
with O
identifying O
the O
most O
optimal O
means O
of O
creating O
an O
AI-ready B-ai_product
workforce I-ai_product
. O

