The O
U.S. B-Org
military I-Org
wants O
to O
expand O
its O
use O
of O
artificial B-ai_tec
intelligence I-ai_tec
in O
warfare, O
but O
says O
it O
will O
take O
care O
to O
deploy O
the O
technology O
in O
accordance O
with O
the O
nation's O
values. O
The O
Pentagon B-Org
outlined O
its O
first O
AI B-ai_tec
strategy O
in O
a O
report O
released O
Tuesday B-Date
. O
The O
plan O
calls O
for O
accelerating O
the O
use O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
systems O
throughout O
the O
military, O
from O
intelligence-gathering O
operations O
to O
predicting O
maintenance O
problems O
in O
planes O
or O
ships. O
It O
urges O
the O
U.S. B-Gpe
to O
advance O
such O
technology O
swiftly O
before O
other O
countries O
chip O
away O
at O
its O
technological O
advantage. O
"Other O
nations, O
particularly O
China B-Gpe
and O
Russia B-Gpe
, O
are O
making O
significant O
investments O
in O
AI B-ai_tec
for O
military O
purposes, O
including O
in O
applications O
that O
raise O
questions O
regarding O
international O
norms O
and O
human O
rights," O
the O
report O
says. O
The O
report O
makes O
little O
mention O
of O
autonomous B-ai_product
weapons I-ai_product
but O
cites O
an O
existing O
2012 B-Date
military O
directive O
that O
requires O
humans O
to O
be O
in O
control. O
The O
U.S. B-Gpe
and O
Russia B-Gpe
are O
among O
a O
handful O
of O
nations O
that O
have O
blocked O
efforts O
at O
the O
United B-Org
Nations I-Org
for O
an O
international O
ban O
on O
" O
killer B-ai_product
robots I-ai_product
" O
— O
fully O
autonomous B-ai_product
weapons I-ai_product
systems O
that O
could O
one O
day O
conduct O
war O
without O
human O
intervention. O
The O
U.S. B-Gpe
has O
argued O
that O
it's O
premature O
to O
try O
to O
regulate O
them. O
The O
strategy O
unveiled O
by O
the O
Department B-Org
of I-Org
Defense I-Org
this O
week O
is O
focused O
on O
more O
immediate O
applications, O
but O
even O
some O
of O
those O
have O
sparked O
ethical O
debates. O
The O
Pentagon B-Org
hit O
a O
roadblock O
in O
its O
AI B-ai_tec
efforts O
last O
year O
after O
internal O
protests O
at O
Google B-Org
led O
the O
tech O
company O
to O
drop O
out O
of O
Project B-ai_program
Maven I-ai_program
, O
which O
uses O
algorithms O
to O
interpret O
aerial O
video O
images O
from O
conflict O
zones. O
Other O
companies O
have O
sought O
to O
fill O
the O
vacuum, O
and O
the O
Pentagon B-Org
is O
working O
with O
AI B-ai_tec
experts O
from O
industry O
and O
academia O
to O
establish O
ethical O
guidelines O
for O
its O
AI B-ai_tec
applications. O
"Everything O
we've O
seen O
is O
with O
a O
human O
decision-maker O
in O
the O
loop," O
said O
Todd B-Person
Probert I-Person
, O
a O
vice O
president O
at O
Raytheon B-Org
's O
intelligence O
division, O
which O
is O
working O
with O
the O
Pentagon B-Org
on O
Maven B-ai_program
and O
other O
projects. O
"It's O
using O
technology O
to O
help O
speed O
up O
the O
process O
but O
not O
supplant O
the O
command O
structure O
that's O
in O
place." O
The O
Pentagon B-Org
's O
report O
follows O
President O
Donald B-Person
Trump I-Person
's O
Monday O
executive O
order O
prioritizing O
AI B-ai_tec
research O
across O
the O
government. O

