SPARKS, O
Nev. O
---- O
Sierra B-Org
Nevada I-Org
Corporation I-Org
( O
SNC B-Org
), O
has O
been O
selected O
to O
participate O
in O
Phase O
3 O
of O
the O
Defense B-Org
Advanced I-Org
Research I-Org
Projects I-Org
Agency I-Org
( O
DARPA B-Org
) O
Gremlins B-ai_program
program I-ai_program
as O
part O
of O
the O
Dynetics-led O
team. O
The O
Gremlins B-ai_program
program I-ai_program
will O
develop O
the O
capability O
to O
launch O
groups O
of O
reusable O
Unmanned B-ai_product
Aerial I-ai_product
Systems I-ai_product
( O
UAS B-ai_product
) O
from O
manned O
aircraft O
while O
out O
of O
range O
of O
adversary O
defenses, O
enhancing O
the O
operational O
flexibility, O
safety O
and O
effectiveness O
of O
U.S. O
military O
air O
operations. O
When O
the O
Gremlins O
complete O
their O
mission, O
a O
C-130 O
transport O
aircraft O
aims O
to O
retrieve O
them O
in O
flight O
and O
return O
them O
to O
base O
for O
maintenance O
and O
preparation O
for O
additional O
missions, O
making O
the O
Gremlins O
a O
low-cost, O
repeatable O
solution. O
SNC B-Org
will O
provide O
the O
Gremlins B-ai_product
Air I-ai_product
Vehicle I-ai_product
( O
GAV B-ai_product
) O
Autonomous B-ai_product
Docking I-ai_product
System I-ai_product
( O
GADS B-ai_product
) O
precision O
navigation, O
guidance O
and O
control O
system O
elements O
essential O
to O
rendezvous O
and O
docking O
of O
the O
GAV B-ai_product
with O
the O
C-130 O
host O
aircraft. O
The O
basic O
architecture O
for O
the O
precision B-ai_tec
navigation I-ai_tec
capability I-ai_tec
( O
PNav B-ai_tec
) O
was O
initially O
developed O
for O
the O
Autonomous B-ai_program
Aerial I-ai_program
Refueling I-ai_program
Demonstration I-ai_program
( O
AARD B-ai_program
) O
and O
UCAS-D B-ai_program
(X-47B) O
programs. O
The O
SNC B-Org
GADS B-ai_product
leverages O
much O
of O
the O
PNav B-ai_tec
technology O
to O
provide O
navigation, O
guidance O
and O
control O
for O
the O
GAV B-ai_product
, O
enabling O
precision O
docking O
for O
recovery. O
The O
Dynetics O
solution O
involves O
deploying O
a O
towed, O
stabilized O
capture O
device O
below O
and O
away O
from O
the O
C-130. O
The O
GAV B-ai_product
is O
designed O
to O
dock O
with O
this O
device O
in O
a O
manner O
similar O
to O
an O
airborne O
refueling O
operation. O
Kutta B-Org
Technology I-Org
, O
an O
SNC B-Org
subsidiary, O
is O
providing O
the O
multi-vehicle B-ai_product
control I-ai_product
services I-ai_product
and O
user B-ai_product
interface I-ai_product
software I-ai_product
for O
Gremlins. O
The O
goal O
is O
to O
provide O
a O
control O
station O
with O
safe, O
intuitive O
work O
flows O
for O
controlling O
multiple O
GAV B-ai_product
simultaneously O
from O
launch O
to O
recovery. O
“Work O
on O
the O
Gremlins B-ai_program
program I-ai_program
leverages O
Kutta’s O
previous O
experience O
with O
safe, O
supervised-autonomous O
vehicle O
control, O
coordinating O
multi-vehicle O
surveillance, O
and O
agent-based, O
manned-unmanned B-ai_tec
teaming I-ai_tec
( O
MUM-T B-ai_tec
),” O
said O
Kutta’s O
Chief O
Operating O
Officer, O
Doug B-Person
Limbaugh I-Person
. O
During O
Phase O
2, O
Kutta O
successfully O
implemented O
the O
control O
station O
prototypes O
for O
all O
operator O
workflows O
and O
established O
test O
plans O
and O
results O
to O
support O
airworthiness. O
The O
Phase O
3 O
effort O
will O
refine O
these O
prototypes O
according O
to O
feedback O
generated O
during O
system O
integrations. O
“ O
SNC B-Org
’s O
past O
accomplishments O
with O
autonomous B-ai_tec
refueling I-ai_tec
and O
precision B-ai_tec
navigation I-ai_tec
were O
a O
perfect O
fit O
for O
what O
Dynetics O
planned O
to O
accomplish O
on O
the O
Gremlins B-ai_program
program I-ai_program
. O
Once O
the O
two O
companies O
came O
together O
to O
discuss O
how O
to O
leverage O
SNC B-Org
’s O
technology, O
both O
recognized O
an O
opportunity O
to O
help O
make O
the O
Dynetics O
team O
even O
more O
competitive,” O
said O
Greg B-Person
Cox I-Person
, O
senior O
vice O
president O
of O
business O
development O
and O
technology O
for O
SNC B-Org
’s O
Electronic O
and O
Information O
Systems O
business O
area. O
“I O
don’t O
believe O
anyone O
questioned O
that O
SNC B-Org
would O
be O
an O
outstanding O
partner O
to O
add O
to O
the O
team. O
I O
know O
we O
were O
certainly O
excited O
about O
joining O
a O
group O
as O
dedicated O
as O
Dynetics.” O
SNC B-Org
joined O
the O
Dynetics O
Gremlins O
team O
following O
completion O
of O
Phase O
1 O
of O
the O
Gremlins B-ai_program
program I-ai_program
. O
Prior O
to O
commencement O
of O
Phase O
2, O
DARPA B-Org
down O
selected O
from O
four O
to O
two O
teams. O
Phase O
2 O
served O
as O
an O
evaluation O
for O
final O
down O
select O
to O
a O
single O
team O
to O
demonstrate O
capabilities O
in O
Phase O
3. O
“It O
doesn’t O
take O
much O
to O
recognize O
SNC B-Org
as O
an O
industry O
leader O
in O
precision B-ai_tec
navigation I-ai_tec
," O
said O
Mark B-Person
Miller I-Person
, O
Dynetics' O
Gremlins B-ai_program
program I-ai_program
manager O
and O
vice O
president O
of O
Missile O
& O
Aviation O
Systems O
Division. O
"With O
the O
many O
challenges O
surrounding O
airborne O
recovery, O
Dynetics O
wanted O
the O
best O
expertise O
and O
experience O
for O
the O
navigation O
and O
docking O
operations, O
and O
that’s O
exactly O
what O
we O
get O
with O
SNC B-Org
.” O
SNC B-Org
continues O
to O
be O
a O
leader O
in O
unmanned O
navigation O
and O
control O
and O
remains O
committed O
to O
developing O
autonomous B-ai_tec
technologies I-ai_tec
. O
The O
SNC B-Org
PNav B-ai_tec
technology O
is O
being O
considered O
for O
autonomous B-ai_tec
aeria I-ai_tec
refueling I-ai_tec
application I-ai_tec
while O
the O
Unmanned B-ai_product
Common I-ai_product
Automated I-ai_product
Recovery I-ai_product
System I-ai_product
, O
Version O
2 O
(UCARS O
V2) O
is O
currently O
fielded O
in O
support O
of O
Department O
of O
Defense O
UAS B-ai_product
operations. O
Sierra B-Org
Nevada I-Org
Corporation I-Org
( O
SNC B-Org
) O
is O
a O
trusted O
leader O
in O
solving O
the O
world’s O
toughest O
challenges O
through O
advanced O
engineering O
technologies O
in O
Space O
Systems, O
Commercial O
Solutions, O
and O
National O
Security O
and O
Defense. O
With O
applications O
including O
navigation B-ai_tec
and O
guidance B-ai_tec
, O
communication B-ai_tec
and O
surveillance B-ai_tec
systems, O
electronic B-ai_tec
warfare I-ai_tec
, O
aircraft B-ai_tec
systems I-ai_tec
and O
telemedicine B-ai_tec
, O
SNC B-Org
provides O
state-of-the O
art O
solutions O
to O
military O
and O
commercial O
customers O
around O
the O
world. O

