The O
artificial B-ai_tec
intelligence I-ai_tec
community O
needs O
to O
put O
a O
lot O
more O
effort O
and O
money O
into O
systems O
protection O
to O
avoid O
it O
costing O
billions O
more O
down O
the O
line, O
according O
to O
the O
founding O
director O
of O
the O
Center B-Org
for I-Org
Security I-Org
and I-Org
Emerging I-Org
Technology I-Org
. O
Jason B-Person
Matheny I-Person
leads O
the O
center, O
a O
shop O
housed O
at O
Georgetown B-MISC
University I-MISC
's O
Walsh B-MISC
School I-MISC
of O
Foreign O
Service O
to O
provide O
policy O
and O
intelligence O
analysis O
to O
the O
government. O
Prior O
to O
launching O
the O
think O
tank, O
Matheny B-Person
was O
assistant O
director O
of O
national O
intelligence, O
and O
before O
that O
he O
served O
as O
director O
of O
IARPA B-ai_program
— O
the O
Intelligence B-ai_program
Advanced I-ai_program
Research I-ai_program
Projects I-ai_program
Activity I-ai_program
. O
He O
currently O
sits O
on O
the O
National B-Org
Security I-Org
Commission I-Org
on I-Org
Artificial I-Org
Intelligence I-Org
. O
Speaking O
from O
that O
vantage O
Sept. B-Date
4 I-Date
during O
a O
panel O
at O
the O
2019 B-MISC
Intelligence I-MISC
and I-MISC
National I-MISC
Security I-MISC
Summit I-MISC
, O
Matheny B-Person
said O
AI B-ai_tec
systems O
are O
not O
being O
developed O
with O
a O
healthy O
focus O
on O
evolving O
threats, O
despite O
increased O
funding O
by O
the O
Pentagon B-Org
and O
the O
private O
sector. O
"A O
lot O
of O
the O
techniques O
that O
are O
used O
today O
were O
built O
without O
intelligent O
adversaries O
in O
mind. O
They O
were O
sort O
of O
innocent." O
For O
Matheny B-Person
, O
there O
are O
three O
main O
types O
of O
attacks O
developers O
need O
to O
consider: O
adversarial B-ai_tec
examples I-ai_tec
, O
trojans B-ai_tec
and O
model B-ai_tec
inversion I-ai_tec
. O
Adversarial B-ai_tec
examples I-ai_tec
are O
attempts O
to O
confuse O
AI B-ai_tec
systems O
by O
tricking O
it O
into O
misclassifying O
data. O
By O
exploiting O
the O
ways O
an O
AI B-ai_tec
system O
processes O
data, O
an O
adversary O
can O
trick O
it O
into O
seeing O
something O
that O
isn't O
there. O
"[It's] O
a O
technique O
that O
an O
adversary O
can O
use O
to O
confuse O
a O
classifier O
into O
thinking O
that, O
for O
instance, O
an O
image O
of O
a O
tank O
is O
instead O
an O
image O
of O
a O
school O
bus O
or O
a O
porpoise. O
It's O
a O
way O
of O
creating O
sort O
of O
an O
optical O
illusion O
for O
a O
machine-learning B-ai_tec
system," O
explained O
Matheny B-Person
. O
While O
adversarial B-ai_tec
examples I-ai_tec
are O
generally O
used O
on O
fully O
developed O
AI B-ai_tec
systems, O
trojan O
attacks O
are O
used O
during O
AI B-ai_tec
development. O
In O
a O
trojan O
attack, O
an O
adversary O
can O
introduce O
a O
change O
in O
the O
environment O
in O
which O
the O
system O
is O
learning, O
which O
causes O
it O
to O
learn O
the O
wrong O
lesson. O
A O
third O
type O
of O
attack, O
called O
model B-ai_tec
inversion I-ai_tec
, O
is O
used O
on O
machine-learning B-ai_tec
systems. O
With O
model B-ai_tec
inversion I-ai_tec
, O
adversaries O
basically O
reverse-engineer O
the O
machine O
learning O
in O
order O
to O
see O
the O
information O
that O
was O
used O
to O
train O
it. O
"So O
if O
you O
have O
a O
bunch O
of O
classified O
data O
that O
is O
going O
into O
a O
model, O
you O
really O
should O
be O
protecting O
the O
model O
even O
after O
it's O
been O
trained O
at O
the O
highest O
level O
of O
classification O
of O
the O
data O
used O
to O
train O
it," O
said O
Matheny B-Person
. O
"Please O
be O
careful O
with O
your O
trained O
models." O
Despite O
these O
three O
vulnerabilities, O
Matheny B-Person
noted O
that O
less O
than O
one O
percent O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
research O
and O
development O
funding O
is O
going O
toward O
AI B-ai_tec
security. O
"In O
some O
of O
the O
same O
ways O
that O
we're O
now O
retrofitting O
most O
IT O
systems O
with O
security O
measures O
that O
are O
meant O
to O
address O
vulnerabilities O
that O
were O
baked O
into O
systems O
in O
the O
1980s B-Date
or O
earlier, O
in O
some O
cases O
we're O
going O
to O
have O
to O
start O
baking O
in O
security O
from O
the O
start O
with O
AI B-ai_tec
, O
unless O
we O
want O
to O
spend O
billions O
of O
dollars O
retrofitting O
security O
years O
from O
now," O
said O
Matheny B-Person
. O

