WASHINGTON B-Gpe
: O
The O
Pentagon B-Org
has O
created O
a O
new O
Joint B-Org
Artificial I-Org
Intelligence I-Org
Center I-Org
( O
JAIC B-Org
) O
that O
will O
have O
oversight O
over O
almost O
all O
service O
and O
defense O
agency O
AI B-ai_tec
efforts. O
This O
coordination O
function O
is O
crucial O
to O
the O
emerging O
AI B-ai_tec
arms O
race O
with O
Russia B-Gpe
and O
China B-Gpe
, O
experts O
told O
us.The O
JAIC B-Org
will O
report O
to O
Chief O
Information O
Officer O
Dana B-Person
Deasy I-Person
, O
the O
establishing O
memo O
by O
Deputy O
Defense O
Secretary O
Patrick B-Person
Shanahan I-Person
says. O
Its O
ambit O
is O
not O
quite O
untrammeled; O
any O
projects O
under O
$15 O
million O
remain O
the O
authority O
of O
the O
service O
or O
agency. O
The O
JAIC B-Org
will O
establish O
a O
common O
set O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
"standards…. O
tools, O
shared O
data, O
reusable O
technology, O
processes, O
and O
expertise" O
for O
the O
whole O
Defense B-Org
Department I-Org
, O
according O
to O
the O
June B-Date
27 I-Date
memo. O
Undersecretary O
for O
Research O
& O
Engineering O
Mike B-Person
Griffin I-Person
, O
a O
far O
more O
prominent O
proponent O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
and O
other O
cutting-edge O
technologies O
who O
has O
warned O
China B-Gpe
and O
Russia B-Gpe
are O
catching O
up O
to O
the O
US B-Gpe
, O
"will O
continue O
to O
promote O
development O
of O
new O
AI B-ai_tec
technologies, O
systems, O
and O
concepts" O
but O
without O
any O
clearly O
specified O
role O
in O
the O
new O
center. O
CIO O
Deasy B-Person
has O
30 O
days O
to O
consult O
the O
rest O
of O
the O
department O
and O
report O
back O
with O
a O
list O
of O
initial O
" O
National B-ai_program
Mission I-ai_program
Initiatives I-ai_program
" O
for O
JAIC B-Org
to O
start O
working O
on O
in O
90 O
days, O
by O
September B-Date
27 I-Date
. O
Even O
though O
that O
start O
date O
is O
just O
three O
days O
before O
the O
end O
of O
fiscal O
year O
2018 B-Date
, O
'18 O
funding O
will O
be O
made O
available O
ASAP O
to O
"enable O
implementation O
of O
select O
AI B-ai_tec
initiatives O
in O
FY O
18," O
the O
memo O
makes O
clear. O
The O
'18 O
funds O
may O
well O
require O
congressional O
approval O
for O
a O
budget O
reprogramming O
action, O
while O
2019 B-Date
money O
will O
require O
an O
amendment O
or O
supplement O
to O
appropriations O
bills O
already O
moving O
through O
Congress. B-Org
Shanahan B-Person
specifies O
that O
the O
first O
National B-ai_program
Mission I-ai_program
Initiative I-ai_program
will O
be O
the O
controversial O
Project B-ai_program
Maven I-ai_program
, O
already O
in O
progress. O
Google B-Org
is O
withdrawing O
from O
its O
Maven B-ai_program
contract O
after O
employees O
objected O
that O
the O
military's O
use O
of O
Google B-Org
AI B-ai_tec
to O
analyze O
surveillance O
video O
could O
be O
used O
to O
target O
lethal O
drone O
strikes. O
( O
Project B-ai_program
Maven I-ai_program
founder O
and O
former O
Deputy O
Defense O
Secretary O
Bob B-Person
Work I-Person
has O
countered O
it O
could O
also O
save O
lives O
by O
killing O
terrorists O
before O
they O
attack O
or O
preventing O
US B-Gpe
strikes O
that O
might O
cause O
collateral O
damage. O
He O
also O
notes O
that O
Google B-Org
is O
working O
with O
elements O
of O
the O
Chinese B-Org
government I-Org
on O
AI B-ai_tec
.) O
No O
doubt O
with O
this O
debate O
in O
mind, O
Shanahan B-Person
writes O
in O
the O
very O
first O
paragraph O
of O
the O
memo O
that O
"we O
must O
pursue O
AI B-ai_tec
applications O
with O
boldness O
and O
alacrity O
while O
ensuring O
strong O
commitment O
to O
military O
ethics O
and O
AI B-ai_tec
safety." O
Shanahan B-Person
directs O
CIO O
Deasy B-Person
to O
consult O
with O
the O
services, O
Joint O
Staff, O
combatant O
commands, O
and O
other O
DoD B-Org
entities O
on O
the O
initial O
list O
of O
National B-ai_program
Mission I-ai_program
Initiatives I-ai_program
. O
Those O
entities, O
in O
return, O
are O
to O
"coordinate" O
with O
the O
CIO O
on O
"each O
AI B-ai_tec
initiative O
that O
totals O
more O
than O
$15 O
million O
annually," O
although O
that O
threshold O
"will O
be O
reviewed O
annually O
as O
investments O
in O
AI B-ai_tec
mature" O
— O
which O
presumably O
means O
it'll O
go O
up O
as O
AI B-ai_tec
projects O
become O
more O
routine. O
(For O
scale, O
Google B-Org
's O
initial O
Project B-ai_program
Maven I-ai_program
contract O
was O
just O
$9 O
million, O
but O
the O
company O
projected O
it O
would O
swiftly O
grow O
to O
$15 O
million O
and O
ultimately O
$250 O
million). O
JAIC B-Org
will O
also O
coordinate O
with O
other O
government O
agencies, O
"industry, O
academics, O
and O
U.S. B-Gpe
allies," O
the O
memo O
says. O
"Harnessing O
the O
strengths O
of O
industry O
and O
academia O
(is O
crucial) O
and O
that O
is O
explicitly O
called O
out," O
said O
Larry B-Person
Lewis I-Person
, O
director O
of O
CNA B-Org
's O
Center O
for O
Autonomy O
and O
AI B-ai_tec
. O
"It's O
not O
necessarily O
going O
to O
be O
easy, O
but O
including O
the O
discussion O
about O
ethics O
and O
AI B-ai_tec
safety O
(so O
prominently) O
is O
going O
to O
be O
an O
important O
piece O
of O
that." O
"I'm O
very O
excited O
to O
hear O
about O
the O
stand O
up O
of O
the O
new O
JAIC B-Org
," O
said O
Bob B-Person
Work I-Person
, O
former O
deputy O
secretary O
of O
defense O
and O
one O
of O
the O
Pentagon B-Org
's O
foremost O
proponents O
of O
artificial O
intelligence. O
"The O
Defense B-Org
Innovation I-Org
Board I-Org
recommended I-Org
the I-Org
Department I-Org
create O
an O
AI B-Org
Center I-Org
of I-Org
Excellence I-Org
nearly O
a O
year O
and O
a O
half O
ago. O
Although O
I O
wish O
it O
had O
not O
taken O
this O
long O
to O
(create O
it), O
the O
JAIC B-Org
is O
an O
important O
step O
forward O
in O
exploring O
and O
pushing O
AI B-ai_tec
and O
machine B-ai_tec
learning I-ai_tec
throughout O
the O
department, O
for O
both O
operational O
and O
business O
applications." O
"The O
JAIC B-Org
's O
initial O
funding O
is O
quite O
modest, O
and O
we O
have O
a O
lot O
to O
learn O
about O
its O
mission O
and O
activities," O
Work B-Person
cautioned. O
"But O
its O
standup O
is O
a O
welcome O
first O
step O
in O
response O
to O
Chinese B-Gpe
, O
and O
to O
a O
lesser O
extent, O
Russia B-Gpe
n, O
plans O
to O
dominate O
these O
technologies." O
"This O
is O
a O
big O
deal," O
CNA B-Org
's O
Lewis B-Person
agreed. O
"This O
is O
an O
acknowledgment O
that O
the O
US B-Gpe
is O
in O
a O
new, O
competitive O
security O
environment O
and O
that O
AI B-ai_tec
is O
likely O
to O
be O
decisive.""It O
gives O
organizational O
focus," O
Lewis B-Person
said O
of O
the O
JAIC B-Org
. O
In O
Shanahan B-Person
's O
memo, O
"it O
talks O
about O
bringing O
to O
bear O
resources O
and O
expertise, O
and O
then O
it O
talks O
about O
providing O
foundational O
pieces O
that O
DoD B-Org
is O
currently O
missing." O
"One O
of O
those O
is O
data O
processes, O
curating O
data," O
Lewis B-Person
continued O
"We O
have O
many O
systems O
out O
there O
that O
collect O
intelligence O
or O
collect O
surveillance, O
but O
we O
don't O
necessarily O
keep O
it O
all, O
and O
we O
don't O
necessarily O
have O
it O
in O
formats O
that O
can O
be O
easily O
exploited O
with O
machine B-ai_tec
learning I-ai_tec
" O
— O
indeed, O
many O
of O
the O
formats O
aren't O
even O
compatible O
with O
each O
other O
— O
"so O
we O
have O
some O
foundational O
work O
to O
do O
to O
be O
able O
to O
bring O
all O
the O
data O
that O
we O
have O
to O
bear." O
Massed O
data O
is O
critical O
because O
modern O
AI B-ai_tec
s O
refine O
their O
algorithms O
through O
machine B-ai_tec
learning I-ai_tec
, O
and O
the O
more O
data O
they O
have O
to O
go O
through, O
the O
better. O
(That's O
assuming O
the O
data O
is O
not O
polluted O
by O
unintentional O
bias O
or O
deliberate O
disinformation). O
Beyond O
creating O
a O
pool O
of O
data, O
the O
JAIC B-Org
mission O
also O
includes O
creating O
common O
processes, O
technologies, O
and O
tools O
that O
all O
of O
DoD B-Org
can O
draw O
on, O
as O
well O
as O
a O
central O
body O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
experts O
to O
consult O
with. O
"You O
don't O
need O
everyone O
to O
be O
a O
PhD O
data O
science O
person," O
Lewis B-Person
said. O
"You O
have O
some O
experts O
that O
can O
develop O
algorithms, O
(but) O
you O
have O
to O
marry O
that O
technical O
expertise O
with O
people O
who O
understand O
(military) O
operations." O

