That O
preserves O
a O
vital O
role O
for O
the O
four O
armed O
services. O
"This O
is O
not O
an O
overly O
centralized O
process," O
Lewis B-Person
said. O
"It O
(the O
memo) O
emphasizes O
several O
times O
this O
is O
in O
collaboration O
with O
the O
services…. O
It O
brings O
focus O
and O
it O
brings O
enablers O
that O
are O
then O
used O
by O
the O
different O
services."What's O
not O
clear O
yet, O
Lewis B-Person
said, O
is O
the O
role O
of O
the O
undersecretary O
for O
research O
and O
engineering, O
Mike B-Person
Griffin I-Person
. O
That's O
something O
that O
the O
Pentagon B-Org
will O
have O
to O
work O
out O
over O
time, O
perhaps O
as O
part O
of O
its O
forthcoming O
AI B-ai_tec
strategy. O
How O
does O
JAIC B-Org
compare O
to O
competitors' O
efforts O
in O
AI B-ai_tec
? O
The O
Chinese B-Org
government I-Org
has O
officially O
made O
global O
dominance O
in O
AI B-ai_tec
a O
national O
priority, O
while O
Russia B-Gpe
constantly O
touts O
its O
combat B-ai_product
robots I-ai_product
field-tested O
in O
Syria B-Gpe
and O
elsewhere. O
"Within O
the O
Russian B-Org
Ministry I-Org
of I-Org
Defense I-Org
, O
there O
are O
now O
two O
centers O
responsible O
for O
the O
development O
of O
the O
latest O
breakthrough O
technologies, O
such O
as O
autonomous B-ai_product
weapons I-ai_product
, O
but O
no O
specific O
agency-wide O
effort O
to O
develop O
AI B-ai_tec
center O
like O
JAIC B-Org
," O
said O
CNA B-Org
scholar O
Sam B-Person
Bendett I-Person
, O
a O
close O
observer O
of O
Russian B-Gpe
military O
technology. O
"On O
the O
other O
hand, O
the O
MOD B-Org
has O
lots O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
and O
other O
high-tech O
R&D O
taking O
place O
amongst O
its O
numerous O
academic O
institutions, O
an O
effort O
that O
the O
MOD B-Org
is O
keen O
on O
consolidating O
further.' O
In O
fact, O
in O
a O
development O
strangely O
reminiscent O
of O
the O
Soviet O
era, O
the O
Russians B-Gpe
are O
actually O
building O
a O
"city" O
on O
the O
Black B-Gpe
Sea I-Gpe
for O
AI B-ai_tec
and O
related O
research, O
with O
a O
planned O
population O
of O
at O
least O
2,000 O
engineers O
and O
scientists O
by O
2020 B-Date
. O
"Currently, O
lots O
of O
efforts O
are O
going O
towards O
the O
establishment O
and O
staffing O
of O
the O
Era O
'technopolis,'" O
said O
Bendett B-Person
, O
"a O
50-acre O
city O
with O
S&T O
and O
R&D O
centers/laboratories O
and O
living O
spaces O
for O
soldiers O
and O
private O
sector O
workers O
who O
will O
be O
developing O
numerous O
projects O
for O
the O
nation's O
military, O
with O
a O
specific O
focus O
on O
AI B-ai_tec
, O
autonomy O
and O
big O
data O
analytics." O
The O
Russians B-Gpe
are O
watching O
US B-Gpe
developments O
closely O
and O
will O
probably O
react O
to O
JAIC B-Org
's O
creation O
with O
"a O
certain O
degree O
of O
apprehension," O
Bendett B-Person
told O
me, O
mainly O
because O
of O
how O
it O
might O
help O
the O
Pentagon B-Org
tap O
into O
America B-Gpe
's O
massive O
private O
sector O
investment O
in O
artificial O
intelligence. O
"Currently, O
Russian B-Gpe
AI B-ai_tec
funding O
is O
only O
a O
small O
fraction O
of O
what O
is O
spent O
in O
the O
US B-Gpe
, O
or O
China B-Gpe
, O
for O
that O
matter," O
he O
said. O
"We O
do O
have O
a O
very O
strong O
commercial O
sector," O
agreed O
fellow O
CNA B-Org
analyst O
Larry B-Person
Lewis I-Person
, O
"but O
unlike O
China B-Gpe
we O
are O
going O
to O
be O
more O
challenged O
to O
leverage O
that O
for O
national O
security, O
as O
we've O
seen O
with O
the O
example O
in O
Google B-Org
." O
Google B-Org
's O
decision O
to O
opt O
out O
of O
a O
military O
contract O
would O
simply O
be O
unthinkable O
for O
a O
Chinese B-Org
company I-Org
, O
he O
told O
me: O
"In O
China B-Gpe
, O
you're O
free O
to O
do O
business O
but O
if O
the O
government O
wants O
something O
of O
yours, O
it's O
theirs." O
"At O
the O
highest O
levels, O
the O
Chinese B-Org
government I-Org
is O
prioritizing O
and O
directing O
strong O
state O
support O
to O
AI B-ai_tec
development, O
leveraging O
and O
harnessing O
the O
dynamism O
of O
the O
'national O
champions,' O
including O
Baidu B-Org
, O
Alibaba B-Org
, O
and O
Tencent B-Org
, O
that O
are O
at O
the O
forefront O
of O
China B-Gpe
's O
AI B-ai_tec
revolution," O
said O
CNAS B-Org
scholar O
Elsa B-Person
Kania I-Person
. O
" O
China B-Gpe
's O
approach O
might O
be O
characterized O
as O
state-driven O
but O
market-centric, O
with O
an O
integrated O
approach O
(combing) O
academia, O
tech O
companies, O
the O
defense O
industry, O
and O
the O
military…..a O
national O
strategy O
of O
civil-military O
fusion." O
"For O
instance, O
Baidu B-Org
is O
partnering O
with O
the O
CETC B-Org
, O
a O
major O
state-owned O
defense O
conglomerate, O
through O
the O
Joint B-Org
Laboratory I-Org
for I-Org
Intelligent I-Org
Command I-Org
and I-Org
Control I-Org
Technologies I-Org
, O
which O
seeks O
to O
advance O
the O
use O
of O
big B-ai_tec
data I-ai_tec
, O
artificial B-ai_tec
intelligence I-ai_tec
, O
and O
cloud B-ai_tec
computing I-ai_tec
for O
military O
command O
and O
information O
systems," O
Kania B-Person
went O
on. O
"This O
spring, O
the O
Chinese B-Org
military I-Org
launched O
what O
might O
be O
characterized O
as O
a O
would-be O
DIUx B-ai_product
with O
Chinese B-Gpe
characteristics. O
This O
'rapid O
response O
team,' O
launched O
in O
Shenzhen B-Gpe
, O
is O
intended O
to O
(enhance) O
the O
PLA B-Org
's O
capability O
to O
leverage O
advanced O
commercial O
technologies O
for O
military O
purposes." O
So O
while O
the O
US B-Gpe
has O
strong O
tradition O
of O
innovation, O
entrepreneurship, O
and O
individual O
creativity, O
China B-Gpe
is O
investing O
heavily O
in O
AI B-ai_tec
, O
its O
capabilities O
are O
growing O
rapidly, O
and O
its O
government O
is O
systematically O
tapping O
civilian O
innovation O
for O
military O
use. O
But O
that's O
not O
all. O
"The O
other O
strength O
that O
they O
have O
is O
they O
have O
lots O
and O
lots O
of O
data" O
to O
train O
machine B-ai_tec
learning I-ai_tec
algorithms I-ai_tec
, O
Lewis B-Person
noted. O
" O
China B-Gpe
has O
many O
more O
people, O
they O
don't O
have O
privacy O
concerns, O
so O
they O
have O
advantages O
there O
that O
we O
don't O
have." O
"The O
major O
challenge O
for O
the O
US B-Gpe
is O
China B-Gpe
," O
Lewis B-Person
said. O
"Not O
only O
do O
they O
have O
comparable O
capabilities O
in O
the O
commercial O
sector, O
which O
is O
really O
important, O
but….they O
have O
a O
national O
strategy. O
They O
are O
approaching O
the O
use O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
just O
like O
the O
US B-Gpe
approached O
going O
to O
the O
moon O
in O
the O
sixties." O

