Google B-Org
wants O
out O
of O
Maven B-ai_program
— O
the O
program O
that O
relies O
on O
artificial O
intelligence O
to O
interpret O
video O
images. O
I O
for O
one O
am O
not O
the O
least O
bit O
surprised. O
By O
way O
of O
background: O
In O
early O
April B-Date
, O
The O
New B-Org
York I-Org
Times I-Org
reported O
3,100 O
Google B-Org
employees O
signed O
a O
letter O
asking O
the O
company O
to O
pull O
out O
of O
the O
program, O
which O
would O
use O
Google B-Org
's O
AI B-ai_tec
technology O
to O
help O
identify O
objects O
in O
drone O
video. O
Those O
objects O
could O
become O
targets, O
employees O
argued, O
and O
they O
didn't O
want O
their O
talents O
being O
used O
or O
potentially O
used O
as O
a O
weapon O
of O
war. O
Wanting O
to O
avoid O
a O
mass O
exodus, O
Google B-Org
told O
employees O
earlier O
this O
month O
that O
it O
would O
not O
renew O
the O
contract O
with O
the O
Pentagon B-Org
after O
the O
current O
deal O
expires O
next O
year. O
My O
colleague O
Mike B-Person
Gruss I-Person
described O
the O
letter O
in O
his O
own O
editorial O
for O
sister O
publication O
C4ISRNET B-Org
as O
an O
act O
of O
pacifism. O
He O
also O
argued O
that O
it O
could O
be O
viewed O
as O
a O
subtle O
attack O
on O
the O
outreach O
to O
the O
tech O
community. O
" O
Pentagon B-Org
leaders O
have O
not O
made O
a O
convincing O
case O
as O
to O
why O
their O
dollars O
and O
their O
vision O
to O
change O
the O
world O
are O
any O
more O
altruistic O
than O
the O
next O
guy O
with O
billion-dollar O
pockets," O
he O
said. O
The O
Pentagon B-Org
wants O
to O
move O
faster O
and O
is O
looking O
to O
Silicon B-Org
Valley I-Org
to O
do O
so, O
but O
Silicon B-Org
Valley I-Org
can't O
quite O
sync O
up O
culturally O
with O
the O
ultimate O
goals O
of O
the O
Pentagon B-Org
, O
he O
added. O
It's O
a O
lost O
cause. O
There O
is O
some O
truth O
in O
that O
argument. O
I'd O
take O
it O
one O
step O
further O
and O
say O
not O
only O
does O
Silicon B-Org
Valley I-Org
have O
a O
hard O
time O
getting O
on O
the O
same O
page O
culturally O
with O
Washington B-Gpe
— O
it O
doesn't O
particularly O
feel O
the O
need O
to O
do O
so. O
The O
returns O
on O
government O
contracts O
are O
lower O
than O
commercial, O
and O
there O
is O
no O
shortage O
of O
opportunities O
in O
their O
own O
sandbox. O
I O
have O
argued O
before O
that O
there O
is O
simply O
not O
enough O
incentive O
for O
such O
companies O
to O
bother. O
But O
if O
a O
more O
pacifist O
culture O
is O
truly O
partially O
to O
blame O
for O
the O
Washington B-Gpe
-tech O
disconnect, O
why O
aren't O
Amazon B-Org
and O
Microsoft B-Org
employees O
raising O
hell O
over O
the O
JEDI B-ai_program
cloud O
contract, O
considering O
it O
in O
theory O
will O
support O
battlefield O
operations? O
One O
could O
perhaps O
argue O
JEDI B-ai_program
is O
a O
simple O
enterprise O
IT O
contract, O
less O
directly O
linked O
to O
warfare O
intelligence. O
But O
if O
the O
Pentagon B-Org
realizes O
the O
full O
vision O
of O
JEDI B-ai_program
, O
all O
of O
the O
drone O
imagery O
could O
ultimately O
live O
in O
that O
cloud O
infrastructure, O
and O
all O
the O
transactions O
of O
data O
sharing O
for O
the O
sake O
of O
intelligence O
would O
in O
whole O
or O
in O
part O
reside O
there. O
It O
would O
be O
a O
hub O
of O
intelligence O
gathering. O
So O
really, O
is O
Maven B-ai_program
that O
much O
different? O
And O
could O
we O
not O
argue O
that O
Maven B-ai_program
supports O
not O
a O
weapon O
of O
war O
but O
rather O
situational O
awareness O
— O
providing O
the O
Pentagon B-Org
with O
more O
granular O
data O
to O
ensure O
it O
doesn't O
make O
frivolous O
decisions O
when O
it O
comes O
to O
strikes? O
Yes, O
the O
decision O
to O
pull O
out O
of O
Maven B-ai_program
does O
reflect O
a O
clash O
of O
cultures. O
But O
in O
this O
particular O
case, O
Google B-Org
's O
employees O
got O
ahead O
of O
the O
marketing O
team O
with O
this O
letter O
— O
owning O
the O
message O
and O
preventing O
the O
company O
or O
the O
Pentagon B-Org
from O
painting O
a O
rosier O
picture O
on O
a O
contract O
that O
could O
be O
interpreted O
in O
any O
number O
of O
ways. O
No O
surprise O
— O
the O
Pentagon B-Org
doesn't O
speak O
about O
such O
things, O
and O
Google B-Org
probably O
followed O
its O
lead, O
hoping O
nobody O
would O
make O
a O
fuss. O
But O
if O
these O
two O
communities O
are O
ever O
to O
coexist, O
there O
just O
may O
need O
to O
be O
a O
little O
more O
handholding. O
And O
let's O
not O
forget O
one O
other O
thing: O
Google B-Org
is O
not O
Amazon B-Org
. O
Amazon B-Org
may O
be O
a O
technological O
marvel, O
but O
it's O
still O
ultimately O
perceived O
as O
an O
e-commerce O
site. O
Politics O
don't O
typically O
get O
in O
the O
way O
of O
its O
empire. O
Google B-Org
— O
much O
like O
Facebook O
and O
other O
social O
media O
applications O
— O
is O
in O
the O
business O
of O
data O
analytics. O
Often O
people's O
data O
for O
that O
matter. O
And O
that O
makes O
everything O
they O
do O
political. O
Just O
ask O
Mark B-Person
Zuckerberg I-Person
. O

