The O
new O
chief O
for O
research O
in O
the O
Pentagon B-Org
is O
building O
an O
artificial B-ai_tec
intelligence I-ai_tec
center, O
pushing O
for O
self-driving B-ai_product
vehicles I-ai_product
in O
combat O
zones O
and O
more O
powerful O
lasers, O
and O
says O
solving O
the O
hypersonic O
gap O
means O
updating O
testing O
facilities. O
Defense B-Org
Undersecretary I-Org
for I-Org
Research I-Org
and I-Org
Engineering I-Org
Michael B-Person
Griffin I-Person
testified O
before O
the O
House B-MISC
Armed I-MISC
Services I-MISC
Committee I-MISC
last O
week, O
answering O
questions O
on O
a O
range O
of O
gear O
and O
procurement O
questions. O
But O
those O
most O
relevant O
to O
service O
members O
included O
weapons O
systems O
on O
the O
horizon O
that O
troops O
could O
see O
in O
combat O
with O
near O
peer O
adversaries. O
More O
rapid O
development O
will O
include O
the O
use O
of O
unmanned B-ai_product
ground I-ai_product
vehicles I-ai_product
in O
formations. O
The O
Army B-Org
recently O
announced O
the O
10th B-Org
Mountain I-Org
Division I-Org
and O
the O
101st B-Org
Airborne I-Org
Division I-Org
will O
have O
a O
robotic O
combat O
vehicle O
called O
the O
Squad B-ai_product
Multipurpose I-ai_product
Equipment I-ai_product
Transport I-ai_product
in O
the O
ranks O
this O
year O
for O
testing, O
which O
will O
develop O
the O
likely O
full-fielding B-ai_product
gear I-ai_product
mule-type I-ai_product
robot I-ai_product
. O
Simple O
tasks, O
such O
as O
delivering O
food, O
mail, O
water O
and O
fuel, O
could O
be O
automated O
sooner O
than O
some O
think, O
Griffin B-Person
said. O
"I O
think, O
frankly, O
we're O
going O
to O
have O
self-driving B-ai_product
vehicles I-ai_product
in O
theater O
for O
the O
Army B-Org
before O
we'll O
have O
self-driving B-ai_product
cars I-ai_product
on O
the O
streets," O
Griffin B-Person
said. O
"If O
that O
can O
be O
done O
by O
an O
automated B-ai_product
unmanned I-ai_product
vehicle I-ai_product
with O
a O
relatively O
simple O
AI B-ai_tec
driving O
algorithm O
where O
I O
don't O
have O
to O
worry O
about O
pedestrians O
and O
road O
signs O
and O
all O
of O
that, O
why O
wouldn't O
I O
do O
that?" O
Griffin B-Person
pointed O
to O
Chinese B-MISC
systems I-MISC
that O
have O
been O
fielded O
or O
can O
be O
soon O
fielded O
that O
can O
launch O
a O
strike O
and O
reach O
out O
"thousands O
of O
kilometers" O
from O
the O
Chinese O
shore O
and O
"hold O
our O
carrier O
battle O
groups O
or O
forward O
deployed O
forces O
on O
land" O
at O
risk. O
"We, O
today, O
do O
not O
have O
systems O
which O
can O
hold O
them O
at O
risk O
in O
a O
corresponding O
manner, O
and O
we O
don't O
have O
defenses O
against O
those O
systems," O
Griffin B-Person
told O
the O
House B-MISC
Armed I-MISC
Services I-MISC
Committee I-MISC
members O
on O
April B-Date
18 I-Date
. O
Another O
Chinese O
technology O
threat O
includes O
the O
nation's O
development O
of O
swarm O
drone B-ai_tec
technologies I-ai_tec
to O
counter O
U.S. B-Gpe
airpower O
and O
other O
strengths. O
That O
means O
getting O
powerful O
laser O
systems O
up O
to O
snuff. O
But O
it O
won't O
happen O
tomorrow. O
"We O
need O
to O
have O
100-kilowatt-class O
weapons O
on O
Army B-Org
theater O
vehicles. O
We O
need O
to O
have O
300-kilowatt-class O
weapons O
on O
Air B-Org
Force I-Org
tankers," O
Griffin B-Person
said. O
"We O
need O
to O
have O
megawatt-class O
directed O
energy O
weapons O
in O
space O
for O
space O
defense. O
These O
are O
things O
we O
can O
do O
over O
the O
next O
decade O
if O
we O
can O
maintain O
our O
focus." O
Scientists O
he's O
been O
talking O
with O
have O
told O
him O
that O
level O
of O
laser O
power O
is O
five O
to O
six O
years O
away O
and O
a O
"megawatt O
laser" O
is O
within O
a O
decade O
with O
persistent O
investment. O
Sen. O
Martin B-Person
Heinrich I-Person
, O
D-N.M., O
pointed O
out O
that O
the O
testing O
facilities, O
such O
as O
White B-MISC
Sands I-MISC
Missile I-MISC
Range I-MISC
in O
his O
state, O
have O
scarcely O
seen O
any O
upgrades O
or O
improvements O
in O
the O
past O
two O
decades, O
despite O
leaps O
in O
technology O
for O
missiles, O
lasers O
and O
other O
items. O
Griffin B-Person
agreed, O
saying O
at O
a O
low O
estimate O
at O
least O
20 O
such O
testing O
facilities O
across O
the O
nation O
are O
in O
the O
same O
situation. O
He O
said O
the O
Defense B-Org
Advanced I-Org
Research I-Org
Projects I-Org
Agency I-Org
does O
most O
of O
the O
leading-edge O
work O
on O
hypersonic O
missile O
systems O
and O
they O
have O
exactly O
one O
testing O
facility, O
a O
NASA B-Org
wind O
tunnel O
near O
Langley B-Gpe
, O
Virginia B-Gpe
. O
"This O
is O
an O
unacceptable O
situation," O
Griffin B-Person
said. O
He O
promised O
to O
return O
with O
budget O
requests O
to O
renovate O
those O
facilities O
to O
improve O
testing. O
Sen. O
Gary B-Person
Peters I-Person
, O
D-Mich., O
asked O
about O
a O
new O
area O
of O
focus O
that O
has O
broad-reaching O
effects: O
artificial B-ai_tec
intelligence I-ai_tec
. O
Griffin B-Person
oversees O
the O
creation O
of O
a O
Joint B-Org
Artificial I-Org
Intelligence I-Org
Center I-Org
that O
would O
create O
AI B-ai_tec
solutions O
for O
all O
the O
service O
branches. O
He O
deferred O
on O
the O
details O
but O
told O
members O
that O
he O
expected O
to O
return O
with O
a O
plan O
within O
two O
months. O
"We O
owe O
the O
Congress B-Org
a O
report, O
I O
think, O
about O
two O
months O
from O
now O
on O
what O
our O
A.I. B-ai_tec
strategy O
will O
be. O
And O
the O
JAIC B-Org
, O
the O
Joint B-Org
Artificial I-Org
Intelligence I-Org
Center I-Org
, O
will O
be O
a O
part O
of O
that O
overall O
strategy," O
Griffin B-Person
said. O
The O
plan O
must O
consider O
the O
592 O
projects O
across O
the O
Defense B-Org
Department I-Org
that O
have O
AI B-ai_tec
as O
part O
of O
their O
development. O

