AI B-ai_tec
technologies O
have O
been O
on O
the O
US B-Gpe
Department B-Org
of I-Org
Defense I-Org
( O
DoD B-Org
) O
radar O
for O
decades. O
Moreover, O
separate O
branches O
of O
the O
military O
(army, O
navy O
and O
air O
force) O
have O
each O
published O
on O
the O
use O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
in O
their O
respective O
domains. O
This O
report O
will O
focus O
on O
the O
general O
DoD B-Org
strategy. O
The O
key O
point O
of O
reference O
is O
the O
2014 B-Date
‘ O
Third B-ai_program
Offset I-ai_program
Strategy I-ai_program
’, O
which O
seeks O
to O
outmanoeuvre O
advantages O
made O
by O
top O
adversaries O
through O
technology. O
As O
the O
then O
Deputy O
Secretary O
of O
Defence B-Org
Bob B-Person
Work I-Person
put O
it O
in O
2016 B-Date
: O
“We O
believe O
quite O
strongly O
that O
the O
technological O
sauce O
of O
the O
Third B-ai_program
Offset I-ai_program
is O
going O
to O
be O
advances O
in O
Artificial B-ai_tec
Intelligence I-ai_tec
( O
AI B-ai_tec
) O
and O
autonomy B-ai_tec
”. O
According O
to O
him O
the O
Third B-ai_program
Offset I-ai_program
’s O
aim O
“is O
to O
exploit O
all O
advances O
in O
artificial B-ai_tec
intelligence I-ai_tec
and O
autonomy B-ai_tec
and O
insert O
them O
into O
DoD B-Org
’s O
battle O
networks O
to O
achieve O
a O
step O
increase O
in O
performance O
that O
the O
department O
believes O
will O
strengthen O
conventional O
deterrence”. O
The O
abovementioned O
2016 B-Date
report O
‘Preparing O
for O
the O
Future O
of O
Artificial B-ai_tec
Intelligence I-ai_tec
’ O
also O
refers O
to O
the O
weaponisation O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
: O
“Given O
advances O
in O
military O
technology O
and O
artificial B-ai_tec
intelligence I-ai_tec
more O
broadly, O
scientists, O
strategists, O
and O
military O
experts O
all O
agree O
that O
the O
future O
of O
LAWS O
is O
difficult O
to O
predict O
and O
the O
pace O
of O
change O
is O
rapid. O
Many O
new O
capabilities O
may O
soon O
be O
possible, O
and O
quickly O
able O
to O
be O
developed O
and O
operationalized. O
The B-Org
Administration I-Org
is O
engaged O
in O
active, O
ongoing O
interagency O
discussions O
to O
work O
toward O
a O
government- O
wide O
policy O
on O
autonomous B-ai_product
weapons I-ai_product
consistent O
with O
shared O
human O
values, O
national O
security O
interests, O
and O
international O
and O
domestic O
obligations.” O
In O
August B-Date
2018 I-Date
, O
a O
Pentagon B-Org
strategy O
report O
noted O
that O
the O
“technologies O
underpinning O
unmanned B-ai_product
systems I-ai_product
would O
make O
it O
possible O
to O
develop O
and O
deploy O
autonomous B-ai_product
systems I-ai_product
that O
could O
independently O
select O
and O
attack O
targets O
with O
lethal O
force” O
but O
that O
commanders O
were O
reluctant O
to O
surrender O
control O
to O
such O
systems, O
in O
part O
due O
to O
lack O
of O
confidence O
in O
the O
machine-learning B-ai_product
system I-ai_product
. O
That O
is O
why O
one O
of O
the O
numerous O
AI B-ai_tec
programmes O
that O
DARPA B-Org
is O
working O
on O
is O
the O
Explainable B-ai_tec
AI I-ai_tec
programme, O
which O
aims O
to O
create O
machine-learning B-ai_tec
techniques O
that O
produce O
more O
explainable B-ai_tec
models I-ai_tec
“while O
maintaining O
a O
high O
level O
of O
learning O
performance”, O
and O
enable O
human O
users O
“to O
understand, O
appropriately O
trust, O
and O
effectively O
manage O
the O
emerging O
generation O
of O
artificially B-ai_tec
intelligent I-ai_tec
partners”. O
A O
day O
after O
the O
White B-Org
House I-Org
’s O
American B-ai_program
AI I-ai_program
Initiative I-ai_program
, O
the O
DoD B-Org
released O
its O
AI B-ai_tec
strategy, O
which O
calls O
for O
the O
rapid O
deployment O
of O
“resilient, O
robust, O
reliable, O
and O
secure” O
AI-enabled B-ai_tec
technologies O
to O
“address O
key O
missions” O
across O
the O
DoD B-Org
”. O
This O
strategy O
puts O
the O
Joint B-Org
Artificial I-Org
Intelligence I-Org
Centre I-Org
( O
JAIC B-Org
) O
at O
the O
forefront O
of O
efforts, O
focusing O
on O
collaborations O
with O
the O
private O
sector O
and O
academia. O
Again, O
this O
AI B-ai_tec
strategy O
is O
unclear O
about O
how O
its O
implementation O
will O
be O
funded. O
The O
US B-Gpe
is O
one O
of O
the O
very O
few O
states O
to O
have O
a O
policy O
specifically O
on O
lethal O
autonomous B-ai_product
weapon I-ai_product
systems I-ai_product
. O
In O
its O
2012 B-Date
3000.09 B-ai_program
Directive I-ai_program
, O
the O
DoD B-Org
states O
that O
“ O
semi-autonomous B-ai_product
weapon I-ai_product
systems I-ai_product
that O
are O
onboard O
or O
integrated O
with O
unmanned B-ai_product
platforms I-ai_product
must O
be O
designed O
such O
that, O
in O
the O
event O
of O
degraded O
or O
lost O
communications, O
the O
system O
does O
not O
autonomously O
select O
and O
engage O
individual O
targets O
or O
specific O
target O
groups O
that O
have O
not O
been O
previously O
selected O
by O
an O
authorized O
human O
operator”. O
The O
regulation O
refers O
to O
“human-supervised O
autonomous B-ai_product
weapons I-ai_product
systems I-ai_product
” O
that O
are O
limited O
to O
military O
purposes, O
prohibits O
the O
“selecting O
of O
humans O
as O
targets” O
and O
allows O
for O
computer- O
controlled O
non-lethal O
systems. O
General O
Paul B-Person
Selva I-Person
, O
the O
second-highest-ranking O
military O
officer O
in O
the O
US B-Gpe
, O
said O
in O
2016 B-Date
that O
the O
US B-Gpe
would O
have O
the O
technology O
within O
a O
decade O
to O
build O
an O
autonomous B-ai_product
system I-ai_product
that O
could O
decide O
on O
its O
own O
who O
and O
when O
to O
kill, O
but O
added O
that O
the O
US B-Gpe
has O
no O
intention O
of O
building O
one. O
That O
same O
year, O
then O
Deputy O
Secretary O
of O
Defense B-Org
Bob B-Person
Work I-Person
also O
confirmed O
that O
when O
it O
comes O
to O
decisions O
over O
life O
and O
death, O
“there O
will O
always O
be O
a O
man O
in O
the O
loop”. O
However, O
there O
is O
a O
loophole O
in O
the O
Directive: O
any O
use O
of O
autonomous B-ai_product
or I-ai_product
semi-autonomous I-ai_product
systems I-ai_product
that O
falls O
outside O
its O
scope O
must O
be O
approved O
by O
three O
top O
Pentagon B-Org
officials. O
But O
what O
they O
consider O
as O
“appropriate O
levels O
of O
human O
judgment O
in O
the O
use O
of O
force” O
is O
left O
undefined. O
Also O
the O
term O
‘human O
in O
the O
loop’ O
does O
not O
appear O
anywhere O
in O
the O
directive. O
“The O
Directive O
does O
not O
use O
the O
phrase O
‘human O
in O
the O
loop,’ O
so O
we O
recommend O
not O
indicating O
that O
DoD B-Org
has O
established O
requirements O
using O
that O
term,” O
according O
to O
a O
DoD B-Org
spokesperson. O
There O
are O
many O
different O
DoD B-Org
programmes O
and O
initiatives O
looking O
at O
military B-ai_product
applications I-ai_product
of I-ai_product
AI I-ai_product
, O
as O
well O
as O
more O
specifically O
at O
autonomous B-ai_product
weapon I-ai_product
systems I-ai_product
. O
According O
to O
DARPA B-Org
itself, O
it O
“has O
played O
a O
leading O
role O
in O
the O
creation O
and O
advancement O
of O
artificial B-ai_tec
intelligence I-ai_tec
( O
AI B-ai_tec
) O
technologies O
that O
have O
produced O
game-changing O
capabilities O
for O
the O
Department B-Org
of I-Org
Defense I-Org
” O
over B-Date
the I-Date
past I-Date
60 I-Date
years I-Date
. O
To O
stay O
ahead O
of O
others, O
especially O
China B-Gpe
, O
the O
US B-Gpe
military O
has O
increased O
its O
commitment. O
In O
September B-Date
2018 B-Date
, O
the O
Pentagon B-Org
pledged O
to O
make O
the O
largest O
investment O
to O
date O
in O
AI B-ai_product
systems I-ai_product
for O
US B-Gpe
weaponry, O
committing O
to O
spend O
USD O
2 O
billion O
over B-Date
the I-Date
next I-Date
five I-Date
years I-Date
through O
DARPA B-Org
to O
“develop O
[the] O
next O
wave O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
technologies”. O
One O
example O
is O
DARPA B-Org
’s O
Collaborative B-ai_program
Operations I-ai_program
in I-ai_program
Denied I-ai_program
Environment I-ai_program
( O
CODE B-ai_program
) O
programme. O
DARPA B-Org
points O
out O
that O
most O
current O
unmanned B-ai_product
aerial I-ai_product
systems I-ai_product
require O
“continuous O
control O
by O
a O
dedicated O
pilot O
and O
sensor O
operator O
supported O
by O
numerous O
telemetry-linked O
analysts”. O
Hence, O
the O
CODE B-ai_program
programme O
aims O
to O
develop O
new O
algorithms O
or O
software O
“for O
existing O
unmanned B-ai_product
aircraft I-ai_product
that O
would O
extend O
mission O
capabilities O
and O
improve O
U.S. B-Gpe
forces’ O
ability O
to O
conduct O
operations O
in O
denied O
or O
contested O
airspace”. O
In O
addition, O
“using O
collaborative O
autonomy B-ai_tec
, O
CODE B-ai_program
-enabled O
unmanned B-ai_product
aircraft I-ai_product
would O
find O
targets O
and O
engage O
them O
as O
appropriate O
under O
established O
rules O
of O
engagement, O
leverage O
nearby O
CODE B-ai_program
-equipped O
systems O
with O
minimal O
supervision, O
and O
adapt O
to O
dynamic O
situations O
such O
as O
attrition O
of O
friendly O
forces O
or O
the O
emergence O
of O
unanticipated O
threats”. O
Testing O
was O
undertaken O
by O
arms O
producers O
Lockheed B-Person
Martin I-Person
and O
Raytheon B-Person
. O
It O
was O
reported O
in O
March B-Date
2019 I-Date
that O
a O
Pentagon B-Org
project O
may O
lead O
to O
the O
world’s O
“first O
large-scale O
armed O
unmanned B-ai_product
warship I-ai_product
”. O
The O
Overlord B-ai_program
programme I-ai_program
“will O
develop O
core O
autonomy B-ai_tec
” O
and O
field O
prototype O
unmanned B-ai_product
surface I-ai_product
vessels I-ai_product
“capable O
of O
being O
seamlessly O
operable O
with O
the O
fleet”. O
Another O
example O
is O
the O
army’s O
Advanced B-ai_program
Targeting I-ai_program
and I-ai_program
Lethality I-ai_program
Automated I-ai_program
System I-ai_program
( O
ATLAS B-ai_program
), O
which O
“will O
use O
artificial B-ai_tec
intelligence I-ai_tec
and O
machine B-ai_tec
learning I-ai_tec
to O
give O
ground-combat O
vehicles O
autonomous B-ai_product
target I-ai_product
capabilities” O
that O
will O
allow O
weapons O
to O
“acquire, O
identify, O
and O
engage O
targets O
at O
least O
3X O
faster O
than O
the O
current O
manual O
process”. O
Still, O
it O
appears O
that O
a O
human O
makes O
the O
final O
decision O
to O
attack O
a O
target. O
The O
United B-Gpe
States I-Gpe
DoD B-Org
recognises O
that O
expertise O
in O
artificial B-ai_tec
intelligence I-ai_tec
lies O
with O
the O
private O
sector, O
and O
specifically O
tech O
companies O
and O
research O
institutes. O
In O
this O
section O
we O
look O
at O
the O
initiatives O
the O
Pentagon B-Org
has O
undertaken O
to O
stimulate O
cooperation, O
the O
challenges O
involved O
in O
that O
cooperation, O
and O
examples O
of O
cooperation O
with O
the O
private O
sector. O
Acknowledging O
the O
innovative O
power O
of O
the O
private O
sector, O
the O
DoD B-Org
is O
keen O
to O
have O
better O
connections O
with O
the O
engineers O
in O
Silicon B-Loc
Valley I-Loc
. O
Indeed, O
recent O
initiatives O
demonstrate O
that O
public-private O
partnership O
is O
a O
US B-Gpe
military O
AI B-ai_tec
priority. O
One O
such O
initiative O
is O
the O
Defense B-Org
Innovation I-Org
Unit I-Org
Experimental I-Org
( O
DIUx B-Org
), O
set O
up O
in O
2015 B-Date
and O
“meant O
to O
serve O
as O
a O
liaison O
between O
the O
Defence B-Org
Department I-Org
and O
the O
tech O
world”. O
The O
DIUx B-Org
contracts O
companies O
“offering O
solutions O
in O
a O
variety O
of O
areas—from O
autonomy B-ai_tec
and O
AI B-ai_tec
to O
human O
systems, O
IT, O
and O
space—to O
solve O
a O
host O
of O
defence O
problems”. O
The O
DIUx B-Org
was O
set O
up O
initially O
as O
an O
experiment, O
but O
in O
August B-Date
2018 I-Date
the O
DoD B-Org
announced O
that O
it O
would O
be O
renamed O
the O
Defense B-Org
Innovation I-Org
Unit I-Org
( O
DIU B-Org
) O
“to O
convey O
a O
sense O
of O
permanence O
to O
the O
agency”. O
Establishing O
collaboration O
with O
private O
companies O
can O
be O
challenging O
as O
well, O
as O
the O
widely O
publicised O
case O
of O
Google B-Org
and O
Project B-ai_program
Maven I-ai_program
has O
shown. O
Launched O
in O
April B-Date
2017 I-Date
, O
the O
objective O
of O
Project B-ai_program
Maven I-ai_program
is O
to O
“turn O
the O
enormous O
volume O
of O
data O
available O
to O
the O
DoD B-Org
into O
actionable O
intelligence O
and O
insights O
at O
speed”. O
To O
do O
so, O
“the O
project O
aims O
to O
develop O
and O
integrate O
‘ O
computer-vision B-ai_tec
algorithms O
needed O
to O
help O
the O
military O
and O
civilian O
analysts O
encumbered O
by O
the O
sheer O
volume O
of O
full-motion O
video O
data O
that O
DoD B-Org
collects O
every O
day O
in O
support O
of O
counterinsurgency O
and O
counterterrorism O
operations,’ O
according O
to O
the O
Pentagon B-Org
”. O
The O
project O
was O
known O
for O
its O
collaboration O
with O
Google B-Org
. O
However, O
following O
protests O
from O
Google B-Org
employees, O
Google B-Org
stated O
that O
it O
would O
not O
renew O
its O
contract. O
Nevertheless, O
other O
tech O
companies O
such O
as O
Clarifai B-Org
, O
Amazon B-Org
and O
Microsoft B-Org
still O
collaborate O
with O
the O
Pentagon B-Org
on O
this O
project. O
The O
Project B-ai_program
Maven I-ai_program
controversy O
deepened O
the O
gap O
between O
the O
AI B-Org
community I-Org
and O
the O
Pentagon B-Org
. O
To O
bridge O
it, O
two O
new O
initiatives O
have O
been O
developed. O
One O
is O
the O
creation O
of O
the O
aforementioned O
JAIC B-Org
with O
the O
goal O
of O
“accelerating O
the O
delivery O
of O
AI-enabled B-ai_tec
capabilities, O
scaling O
the O
Department- O
wide O
impact O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
, O
and O
synchronizing O
DoD B-Org
AI B-ai_tec
activities O
to O
expand O
Joint O
Force O
advantages”, O
by O
“collaborating O
within O
DoD B-Org
, O
across O
government, O
and O
with O
industry, O
academia, O
and O
US B-Gpe
allies O
to O
strengthen O
partnerships, O
highlight O
critical O
needs, O
solve O
problems O
of O
urgent O
operational O
significance, O
and O
adapt O
AI B-ai_tec
technologies O
for O
DoD B-Org
missions”. O
As O
a O
result O
of O
this O
controversy, O
the O
DoD B-Org
is O
working O
on O
a O
new O
review O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
ethics O
through O
the O
Defense B-ai_program
Innovation I-ai_program
Board I-ai_program
( O
DIB B-ai_program
). O
It O
aims O
to O
develop O
principles O
for O
the O
use O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
by O
the O
military, O
“particularly O
while O
the O
adoption O
of O
this O
technology O
is O
at O
a O
nascent O
stage”. O
According O
to O
the O
DIB B-ai_program
, O
“these O
AI B-ai_program
Principles I-ai_program
should O
demonstrate O
DoD B-Org
’s O
commitment O
to O
deter O
war O
and O
use O
AI B-ai_tec
responsibly O
to O
ensure O
civil O
liberties O
and O
the O
rule O
of O
law O
are O
protected”. O
At O
the O
same O
time, O
there O
is O
a O
long O
history O
of O
tech O
sector O
cooperation O
through O
DARPA B-Org
programmes. O
One O
recent O
example O
is O
the O
OFFSET B-ai_program
programme O
( O
OFFensive B-ai_program
Swarm-Enabled I-ai_program
Tactics I-ai_program
), O
with O
the O
aim O
of O
“using O
swarms O
compromising O
upwards O
of O
250 O
unmanned B-ai_product
aircraft I-ai_product
systems I-ai_product
( O
UASs B-ai_product
) O
and/or O
unmanned B-ai_product
ground I-ai_product
systems I-ai_product
( O
UGSs B-ai_product
) O
to O
accomplish O
diverse O
missions O
in O
complex O
urban O
environments”. O
This O
programme O
is O
being O
undertaken O
in O
collaboration O
with O
Carnegie B-Org
Mellon I-Org
University I-Org
, O
Cornell B-Org
University I-Org
, O
Michigan B-Org
Technological I-Org
University I-Org
and O
others, O
as O
well O
as O
with O
start-ups O
such O
as O
Corenova B-Org
Technologies I-Org
, O
Inc. O
Another O
programme O
is O
the O
Squad B-ai_program
X I-ai_program
Experimentation I-ai_program
Programme I-ai_program
, O
which O
is O
exploring O
four O
key O
technical O
areas: O
precision O
engagement, O
non-kinetic O
engagement, O
squad B-ai_product
sensing I-ai_product
and O
squad B-ai_product
autonomy I-ai_product
. O
The O
aim O
of O
the O
programme O
is O
for O
human O
fighters O
to O
“have O
a O
greater O
sense O
of O
confidence O
in O
their O
autonomous B-ai_product
partners I-ai_product
, O
as O
well O
as O
a O
better O
understanding O
of O
how O
the O
autonomous B-ai_product
systems I-ai_product
would O
likely O
act O
on O
the O
battlefield”, O
as O
well O
as O
to O
“extend O
and O
enhance O
the O
situational O
awareness O
of O
small, O
dismounted O
units”. O
In O
this O
programme, O
Lockheed B-Org
Martin I-Org
Missiles I-Org
is O
working O
on O
approaches O
to O
“provide O
unique O
capabilities O
to O
enhance O
ground O
infantries”. O
One O
of O
the O
most O
publicised O
programmes O
is O
the O
Joint B-ai_program
Enterprise I-ai_program
Defense I-ai_program
Infrastructure I-ai_program
( O
JEDI B-ai_program
), O
aiming O
to O
use O
“commercial O
cloud O
services O
to O
transform O
how O
DoD B-Org
captures, O
processes, O
understands, O
and O
harnesses O
its O
data O
to O
deliver O
advanced O
capabilities, O
enable O
real-time O
decision-making, O
and O
support O
joint O
force O
operations”. O
It O
has O
been O
reported O
that O
“the O
real O
force O
driving O
Jedi O
is O
the O
desire O
to O
weaponize O
AI B-ai_tec
—what O
the O
defence O
department O
has O
been O
calling O
‘ O
algorithmic B-ai_product
warfare I-ai_product
’. O
By O
pooling O
the O
military’s O
data O
into O
a O
modern O
cloud O
platform, O
and O
using O
the O
machine-learning B-ai_tec
services O
that O
such O
platforms O
provide O
to O
analyse O
the O
data, O
JEDI B-ai_program
will O
help O
the O
Pentagon B-Org
realize O
its O
AI B-ai_tec
ambitions”. O
The O
JEDI B-ai_program
contract O
is O
reportedly O
worth O
US B-Gpe
D O
10 O
billion, O
and O
many O
big O
tech O
companies O
have O
submitted O
bids, O
including O
Microsoft B-Org
, O
Oracle B-Org
and O
IBM B-Org
. O
Amazon B-Org
is O
believed O
to O
be O
the O
main O
contender. O
DARPA B-Org
also O
has O
the O
Gremlins B-ai_program
programme I-ai_program
. O
The O
programme O
“envisions O
launching O
groups O
of O
UASs B-ai_product
from O
existing O
large O
aircraft O
such O
as O
bombers O
or O
transport O
aircraft O
[…] O
while O
those O
planes O
are O
out O
of O
range O
of O
adversary O
defences”. O
The O
rationale O
is O
that O
being O
able O
to O
send O
larger O
numbers O
of O
UASs B-ai_product
“with O
coordinated, O
distributed O
capabilities” O
could O
provide O
the O
US B-Gpe
with O
better O
operational O
flexibility O
at O
a O
much O
lower O
cost. O
In O
May B-Date
2018 I-Date
, O
it O
was O
announced O
that O
the O
Phase O
III O
contract O
had O
been O
awarded O
to O
Dynetics B-Org
. O
In O
February B-Date
2019 I-Date
, O
it O
was O
announced O
that O
the O
DoD B-Org
is O
launching O
the O
US B-ai_program
Army’s I-ai_program
Artificial I-ai_program
Intelligence I-ai_program
Task I-ai_program
Force I-ai_program
in O
collaboration O
with O
Carnegie B-Org
Mellon I-Org
University I-Org
( O
CMU B-Org
). O
The O
location O
of O
this O
task O
force O
will O
allow O
the O
army O
to O
work O
closely O
with O
CMU B-Org
as O
well O
as O
other O
universities O
and O
companies O
in O
the O
Pittsburgh B-Gpe
region. O
The O
DoD B-Org
is O
investing O
US B-Gpe
D O
72 O
million O
in O
the O
five-year O
effort. O
“Tackling O
difficult O
science O
and O
technology O
challenges O
is O
rarely O
done O
alone O
and O
there O
is O
no O
greater O
challenge O
or O
opportunity O
facing O
the O
Army O
than O
Artificial B-ai_tec
Intelligence I-ai_tec
,” O
said O
the O
director O
of O
the O
army’s O
corporate O
laboratory. O

