WASHINGTON B-Gpe
— O
The O
F-35 B-MISC
and O
F-15EX B-MISC
fighter O
jets O
could O
get O
drone O
wingmen O
in O
the O
coming O
years, O
the O
U.S. B-Gpe
Air B-Org
Force I-Org
's O
top O
acquisition O
official O
revealed O
to O
Defense B-Org
News I-Org
. O
The O
service O
is O
exploring O
ways O
to O
team O
Lockheed B-Org
Martin I-Org
's O
F-35 B-MISC
and O
Boeing B-Org
's O
new O
F-15EX B-MISC
with O
the O
XQ-58 B-ai_product
Valkyrie I-ai_product
drone I-ai_product
— O
a O
low-cost O
attritable O
fighter O
made O
by O
Kratos B-Org
Defense I-Org
— O
or O
similar O
unmanned O
platforms. O
Attritable O
means O
that O
an O
asset O
is O
reusable, O
but O
inexpensive O
enough O
that O
the O
service O
can O
afford O
to O
lose O
it O
in O
battle. O
The O
Air B-Org
Force I-Org
is O
in O
discussions O
with O
Boeing B-Org
and O
Lockheed B-Org
on O
the O
prospect, O
and O
the O
Air B-Org
Force I-Org
Research I-Org
Laboratory I-Org
is O
working O
on O
the O
technology, O
Will B-Person
Roper I-Person
said O
May B-Date
21 I-Date
in O
an O
exclusive O
interview. O
"I'm O
very O
passionate O
about O
doing O
it, O
and O
the O
F-35 B-MISC
has O
a O
wonderful O
opportunity O
to O
do O
this O
as O
part O
of O
Block O
4," O
Roper B-Person
said, O
referring O
to O
the O
F-35 B-MISC
's O
upcoming O
upgrade O
program. O
"We O
might O
also O
have O
an O
opportunity O
to O
do O
this O
as O
part O
of O
F-15EX B-MISC
." O
Roper B-Person
told O
lawmakers O
this O
month O
that O
Valkyrie B-ai_product
would O
transition O
to O
a O
prototype O
program O
known O
as O
Skyborg B-ai_program
, O
where O
the O
drone O
will O
be O
outfitted O
with O
new O
sensors O
and O
payloads O
and O
will O
be O
networked O
to O
manned O
fighter O
jets. O
In B-Date
March I-Date
, O
he O
characterized O
Skyborg B-ai_program
as O
an O
artificial B-ai_tec
intelligence I-ai_tec
wingman O
that O
would O
train O
and O
learn O
alongside O
pilots, O
or O
possibly O
be O
incorporated O
into O
a O
manned O
fighter O
cockpit O
to O
act O
as O
an O
assistant O
to O
the O
pilot O
like O
R2-D2 B-MISC
in O
the O
"Star O
Wars" O
films. O
But O
until O
now, O
the O
Air B-Org
Force I-Org
had O
not O
identified O
the O
platforms O
are O
under O
consideration O
to O
be O
equipped O
with O
Skyborg B-ai_program
or O
teamed O
with O
the O
XQ-58 B-ai_product
Valkyrie I-ai_product
. O
The O
Valkyrie B-ai_product
, O
which O
flew O
its O
first O
test O
flight O
at O
Yuma B-MISC
Proving I-MISC
Ground I-MISC
, O
Arizona, B-Gpe
on O
March B-Date
5 I-Date
, O
was O
designed O
to O
perform O
and O
maneuver O
like O
a O
fighter O
jet. O
It O
can O
fly O
at O
high O
subsonic O
speeds, O
takeoff O
without O
a O
runway, O
and, O
according O
to O
Kratos, B-Person
meet O
or O
exceed O
the O
Air B-Org
Force I-Org
's O
requirement O
for O
a O
1,500-nautical-mile O
range O
with O
a O
500-pound O
payload. O
When O
produced O
in O
volume, O
Roper B-Person
predicted O
that O
they O
will O
cost O
"a O
couple O
million O
bucks" O
each O
— O
not O
cheap, O
but O
inexpensive O
compared O
to O
the O
F-35 B-MISC
A O
and O
F-15EX B-MISC
, O
which O
are O
expected O
to O
cost O
about O
$80 O
million O
per O
jet O
over O
the O
same O
time O
frame. O
The O
Air B-Org
Force I-Org
is O
also O
assessing O
whether O
other O
unmanned B-ai_product
aerial I-ai_product
systems I-ai_product
would O
complement O
the O
Skyborg B-ai_program
program. O
A O
March O
request O
for O
information O
describes O
"a O
modular, O
fighter-like O
aircraft" O
that O
is O
autonomous O
and O
attritable, O
with O
open O
systems O
that O
allow O
it O
to O
be O
updated O
with O
new O
AI B-ai_tec
software O
or O
new O
hardware. O
Desired O
characteristics O
include O
the O
ability O
to O
detect O
and O
avoid O
obstacles O
and O
bad O
weather, O
and O
to O
takeoff O
and O
land O
autonomously. O
According O
to O
the O
solicitation, O
an O
"autonomous O
airborne O
system O
experimental O
campaign" O
could O
occur O
in O
fiscal O
years O
2019 B-Date
and O
2020 B-Date
, O
with O
the O
hope O
of O
having O
an O
aircraft O
ready O
by O
2023 B-Date
. O
Roper B-Person
said O
teaming O
fighters O
with O
drones O
could O
"open O
up O
the O
door O
for O
an O
entirely O
different O
way O
to O
do O
aerial O
combat." O
For O
example, O
take O
a O
typical O
four-aircraft O
formation O
and O
replace O
it O
with O
an O
F-15EX B-MISC
and O
three O
Valkyrie B-ai_product
s. O
"We O
can O
take O
risk O
with O
some O
systems O
to O
keep O
others O
safer," O
Roper B-Person
said. O
"We O
can O
separate O
the O
sensor O
and O
the O
shooter. O
Right O
now O
they're O
collocated O
on O
a O
single O
platform O
with O
a O
person O
in O
it. O
In O
the O
future, O
we O
can O
separate O
them O
out, O
put O
sensors O
ahead O
of O
shooters, O
put O
our O
manned O
systems O
behind O
the O
unmanned. O
There's O
a O
whole O
playbook." O
For O
the O
F-35 B-MISC
, O
the O
pathway O
to O
incorporating O
Skyborg B-ai_program
would O
involve O
writing O
software O
— O
similar O
to O
an O
iPhone O
application O
—that O
could O
be O
installed O
on O
the O
jet O
during O
its O
Block O
4 O
modernization O
phase O
in O
the O
early B-Date
2020s I-Date
. O

