Starting O
in O
2023 B-Date
, O
F-35 B-MISC
s O
rolling O
off O
the O
production O
line O
will O
be O
outfitted O
with O
improved O
processors, O
more O
memory O
capacity O
and O
new, O
advanced O
displays O
in O
the O
cockpit O
— O
a O
suite O
of O
changes O
that O
the O
F-35 B-MISC
program O
office O
calls O
" O
tech B-ai_program
refresh I-ai_program
3 I-ai_program
." O
Undergirding O
those O
upgrades O
is O
a O
transition O
to O
an O
open O
mission O
system O
architecture O
owned O
by O
the O
government, O
which O
will O
allow O
the O
services O
to O
create O
and O
upload O
custom O
software O
apps, O
F-35 B-MISC
program O
head O
Vice O
Adm. O
Mat B-Person
Winter I-Person
told O
reporters O
this O
month. O
In O
a O
statement, O
Lockheed B-Org
spokesman O
Mike B-Person
Friedman I-Person
said O
the O
F-35 B-MISC
is O
"ideally O
suited" O
for O
manned-unmanned O
teaming O
applications O
like O
Skyborg. B-ai_program
"Unlike O
4th O
generation O
aircraft, O
the O
F-35 B-MISC
is O
a O
force O
multiplier O
able O
to O
share O
its O
operational O
picture O
with O
ground, O
sea O
and O
air O
assets O
in O
the O
battlespace," O
Friedman B-Person
said. O
" O
Lockheed B-Org
Martin I-Org
has O
extensive O
experience O
in O
manned/unmanned O
teaming O
and O
are O
working O
closely O
with O
our O
customers O
to O
develop O
and O
field O
this O
critical O
capability. O
Any O
timing O
for O
integration O
would O
be O
determined O
by O
our O
customers O
through O
the O
Continuous O
Capability, O
Development O
and O
Delivery O
(C2D2) O
framework O
for O
Follow O
on O
Modernization O
(FOM)." O
Meanwhile, O
Congress B-Org
must O
first O
decide O
whether O
to O
fund O
the O
F-15EX B-ai_program
program I-ai_program
— O
a O
likely O
prospect O
considering O
the O
draft B-Org
House I-Org
appropriations O
bill O
includes O
$986 O
million O
for O
eight O
jets. O
Boeing O
appears O
receptive O
to O
the O
potential O
upgrade. O
In O
an O
emailed O
statement, O
Prat B-Person
Kumar I-Person
, O
the O
company's O
vice O
president O
for O
the O
F-15 B-ai_program
program I-ai_program
, O
acknowledged O
the O
company O
is O
in O
talks O
with O
the O
Air B-Org
Force I-Org
about O
a O
pathway O
to O
incorporate O
the O
F-15EX B-ai_program
into O
Skyborg. B-ai_program
"We O
are O
initiating O
early O
discussions O
with O
the O
U.S. B-Org
Air I-Org
Force I-Org
customer O
on O
how O
to O
insert O
contemporary O
technology O
such O
as O
this," O
he O
said. O
"The O
F-15EX B-ai_program
is O
a O
uniquely O
suited O
platform O
for O
such O
tech O
insertions O
as O
it O
has O
available O
computing O
capacity O
and O
space O
to O
continue O
offering O
new O
capabilities O
to O
the O
warfighter." O
The O
biggest O
challenges, O
Roper B-Person
said, O
may O
be O
technological O
and O
cultural O
— O
not O
financial. O
"I O
don't O
think O
there's O
a O
barrier O
in O
terms O
of O
funding," O
he O
said. O
"This O
is O
just O
different. O
There O
are O
going O
to O
be O
human O
factors, O
so O
how O
do O
you O
get O
a O
simulator O
to O
get O
you O
to O
do O
this? O
How O
do O
you O
get O
the O
AI B-ai_tec
in O
the O
attritable O
system? O
What O
do O
you O
do? O
What O
do O
you O
not O
allow O
it O
to O
do?" O
When O
Roper B-Person
recently O
visited O
the O
Massachusetts O
Institute O
of O
Technology, O
the O
scientists O
he O
spoke O
to O
acknowledged O
that O
their O
AI B-ai_tec
research O
is O
driven O
by O
near-term O
commercial O
applications, O
like O
extending O
internet O
connectivity O
into O
everyday O
electronics. O
A O
future O
generation O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
, O
like O
self-driving B-ai_product
cars I-ai_product
, O
will O
have O
to O
grapple O
with O
questions O
of O
trust O
and O
audibility, O
Roper B-Person
added. O
But O
the O
AI B-ai_tec
the O
Pentagon B-Org
wants O
would O
have O
to O
be O
more O
advanced O
from O
the O
get-go O
if O
the O
U.S. B-Org
military I-Org
is O
to O
protect O
itself O
from O
adversaries O
seeking O
to O
exploit O
system O
capabilities O
— O
such O
as O
pattern B-ai_tec
recognition I-ai_tec
, O
feature B-ai_tec
recognition I-ai_tec
and O
data B-ai_tec
extraction I-ai_tec
— O
by O
feeding O
it O
false O
information. O
"The O
current O
generation O
of O
AI B-ai_tec
does O
not O
deal O
with O
a O
world O
that O
understands O
how O
AI B-ai_tec
works O
and O
intentionally O
trying O
to O
throw O
a O
wrench O
in O
its O
machine. O
We O
will O
deal O
with O
that," O
Roper B-Person
explained. O
"We O
need O
to O
understand O
when O
the O
machine O
will O
be O
at O
its O
best O
and O
when O
the O
human O
will O
at O
its O
best. O
… O
We O
will O
need O
to O
get O
the O
person O
trained O
to O
have O
an O
instinct O
for O
AI B-ai_tec
just O
like O
they O
have O
an O
instinct O
for O
stealth," O
he O
said. O
"When O
is O
their O
AI B-ai_tec
giving O
them O
an O
advantage, O
and O
when O
is O
it O
not?" O

